[
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |Departure path straight out|Takeofftime 1030 2Z|Winds during climb 180\ndegrees at 30 kts, True course during climb 160 degrees, Airport elevation 1,500 ft, True\nairspeed 125 Kts, Rate of climb 500 ftmin, What would be the distance and time upon\nreaching 8,500 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "23 NM and 1044Z\n",
        "choiceone": "20 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When planning a distance flight, true course measurements on a Sectional Aeronautical\nChart should be made at a meridian near the midpoint of the course because the\n",
        "answer": "angles formed by lines of longitude and the course line vary from point to point.\n",
        "choiceone": "values of isogonic lines change from point to point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angles formed by isogonic lines and lines of latitude vary from point to point.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 240 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 25\nmiles off course. If 100 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "21degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 238 degrees\nVariation 3 degrees W\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\n\nAmbient temperature -15 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 8,500 ft|Forecast wind 160 degrees at 25 kts|Under these\n",
        "answer": "233 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "224 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "241degrees and 178 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 135 degrees results in a ground track of 130 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 135 knots results in a groundspeed of 140 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "246 degrees and 13 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "019 degrees and 12 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 degreesand 13 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view Annex 061-600199)\nWhich figure in the Appendix represents the geographic latitude of position P, which is\nsituated above the surface of the ellipsoid?\n\n",
        "answer": "figure A\n",
        "choiceone": "figure B\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure C\n",
        "choicethree": "figure D\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal:\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at latitude 10\u00b0 South flies north at a GS of 890 km/h.\n\nWhat will its latitude be after 1.5 hour?\n",
        "answer": "02\u00b000'N\n",
        "choiceone": "12\u00b015'N\n",
        "choicetwo": "22\u00b000'N\n",
        "choicethree": "03\u00b050'N\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Cor\nthe:\n\nchart earth convergency is most accurately represented at\n",
        "answer": "parallel of origin\n",
        "choiceone": "north and south limits of the chart\n",
        "choicetwo": "standard parallels\n",
        "choicethree": "Equator\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\nWhat is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME (N5150.4 W00829.7) to position\nN5210 W00920?\n",
        "answer": "11\u00b0 - 38NM\n",
        "choiceone": "350\u00b0 - 22NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "295\u00b0 - 38NM\n",
        "choicethree": "170\u00b0 - 22NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n\nCRK VOR N5150.4 W00829.7,\n\nAircraft position N5220 W00910\n\nWhich of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position?\n\n",
        "answer": "SHA 214\u00b0\nCRK 330\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 025\u00b0\nCRK 141\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 205\u00b0\nCRK 321\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 033\u00b0\nCRK 149\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is descending down a 6% slope whilst maintaining a GS of 300 kt.\nThe rate of descent of the aircraft is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1800 fumin\n",
        "choiceone": "10800 ftmin\n",
        "choicetwo": "3600 fmin\n",
        "choicethree": "900 fmin\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1023 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "11.1NM\n",
        "choiceone": "10.3 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "16.6 NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The True course in the flight log is 270\u00b0, the forecast wind is 045\u00b0(T)/15kt and the TAS is\n\n120kt.\nAfter 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM South of the\n\nintended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position.\nThe track angle error (TKE) is:\n",
        "answer": "5\u00b0L\n",
        "choiceone": "6R\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\u00b0L\n",
        "choicethree": "SR\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 111.) In which general direction from the VORTAC is the aircraft\nlocated?\n",
        "answer": "Northwest.\n",
        "choiceone": "Northeast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southeast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft's DME receiver will not accept rey\nreflected from the ground or clouds, because of the:\n\nown interrogations that are\n",
        "answer": "interrogation and reply frequencies being 63 MHz apart;\n",
        "choiceone": "random PRF which is unique to each aircraft;\n",
        "choicetwo": "interrogation pulses being transmitted in pairs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 139.) Which OBS selection on the No. 1 NAV would center the CDI and\nchange the ambiguity indication to a TO?\n",
        "answer": "165\n",
        "choiceone": "175\n",
        "choicetwo": "345\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two radio aids to navigation that may share a common receiving aerial, are:\n",
        "answer": "ADF and Loran C;\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR and ADF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "ILS and ADF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "For HF communication at night the frequency selected should be:\n",
        "answer": "Half the day frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "Twice the day frequency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Same as the day frequency.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fading of LF and MF at night may be due to:\n",
        "answer": "Simultaneous reception of sky waves and surface waves.\n",
        "choiceone": "Poor receiver sensitivity and ionospheric attenuation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reception of space waves and atmospheric attenuation.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A modern ADF uses a:\n",
        "answer": "Horizontal crossed loop aerial with a orthogonal pair of coils wound on a ferrite core\nfed to a goniometer and combined with the signal from a sense aerial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Horizontal crossed loop aerial with an orthogonal pair of coils wound on a ferrite\ncore fed to a goniometer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pair of coils which rotate about a ferrite core combined with a signal from a sense\naerial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wavelength of an NDB transmitting on 375 KHz?\n",
        "answer": "800m\n",
        "choiceone": "8000 m\n",
        "choicetwo": "8m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft's heading is 070\u00b0 (M) Variation 10\u00b0E . An NDB bears 200 relative. The RMI\nwill indicate:\n",
        "answer": "270.\n",
        "choiceone": "260;\n",
        "choicetwo": "280;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is heading 340(M) and is 30 nm from the VOR on a bearing of 142 from the\nVOR. The pilot has selected 146 on the OBS and the TO/FROM indicator shows FROM.\nWhat would the indication be on a 5 dot VOR indicator?\n",
        "answer": "2 dots fly right.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 dots fly left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 dots fly right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A DME transponder becomes saturated if interrogated by a excessive number of\naircraft. It will reply to the nearest :\n",
        "answer": "100 aircraft,\n",
        "choiceone": "80 aircraft,\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 aircraft.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The heading rose of an HSI is frozen on 200\u00b0. Lined up on the ILS of runway 25, the\nlocaliser needle will be:\n",
        "answer": "centred\n",
        "choiceone": "left of centre\n",
        "choicetwo": "right of centre\n",
        "choicethree": "centred with the \u2018fail\u2019 flag showing\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum range of search radar is dependant on the:\n",
        "answer": "pulse recurrence frequency;\n",
        "choiceone": "radio frequency;\n",
        "choicetwo": "pulse width.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (1).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 150 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 8\nmiles off course. If 160 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "6 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 238 degrees\nVariation 3 degrees W\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\n\nAmbient temperature -15 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 8,500 ft|Forecast wind 160 degrees at 25 kts|Under these\n",
        "answer": "233 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "224 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "241degrees and 178 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 240 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 25\nmiles off course. If 100 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "21degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Departure path straight out|Takeoff time 1435Z|Winds during climb 175 degrees at 25\nkts, True course during climb 155 degrees Airport elevation 2,000 ft|True ai\nkts|Rate of climb 500 fmin|What would be the distance and time upon react\nfeet MSL?\n\n",
        "answer": "21 NM and 1447Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "27 NM and 1455Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 NM and 1452Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point C to point A of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "wind direction and velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true heading and groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view Annex 061-600199)\nWhich figure in the Appendix represents the geographic latitude of position P, which is\nsituated above the surface of the ellipsoid?\n\n",
        "answer": "figure A\n",
        "choiceone": "figure B\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure C\n",
        "choicethree": "figure D\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many small circles can be drawn between any two points on a sphere?\n",
        "answer": "An unlimited number.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One.\n",
        "choicethree": "Two.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal:\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR (N5243.3 W00853.1) radial 205\u00b0,\nCRK VOR (N5150.4 W00829.7) radial 317\u00b0.\nWhat is the aircraft position?\n",
        "answer": "N5210 W00910\n",
        "choiceone": "N5118 W00913\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5205 wo0915\n",
        "choicethree": "N5215 W00917\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nistance from A to B = 84 NM.\n\nWhat is the time from A to B?-\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 45\u00b0 left of the nose and 3 MIN\nlater on a relative bearing of 90\u00b0 left of the nose.\nThe WIV is calm; aircraft GS 180 kt.\n\nWhat is the minimum distance between the aircraft and the ground feature?\n",
        "answer": "9NM\n",
        "choiceone": "12NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "3NM\n",
        "choicethree": "6NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent when 100 NM from a DME facility\nand to cross the station at FL120. If the mean GS during the descent is 396 kt, the\nminimum rate of descent required is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1650 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "2400 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1550 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1023 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "11.1NM\n",
        "choiceone": "10.3 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "16.6 NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-9438A)\nComplete line 2 of the \"FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u2019, positions 'C' to 'D'.\n\nWhat is the HDG*(M) and ETA?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1239 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 188\u00b0 - ETA 1229 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1249 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 183\u00b0 - ETA 1159 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 42.) At which aircraft position(s) would you receive OMNI indication X?\n",
        "answer": "1 and 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 and 7.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During day time the ionosphere is split into the following three distinct layers:\n",
        "answer": "D layer, Kennelly-Heaviside layer, Appleton layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "E layer, Appleton layer, F layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "D layer, Kennelly-Heaviside layer, E layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The F layer of the ionosphere is called the:\n",
        "answer": "Appleton layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Kennelly-Heaviside layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gauss layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a radio wave crosses the coast, leaves the land or passes over the sea the speed\nincreases. When this happens:\n",
        "answer": "The wavelength changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "The frequency changes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No change in either.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying a constant heading with 8 starboard drift and is making good a track\nparallel to the centreline of an airway but 5 nm off to the left of the centreline. Estimate\nthe ADF reading on an NDB on the centreline but 42 nm ahead.\n",
        "answer": "015 relative\n",
        "choiceone": "359 relative\n",
        "choicetwo": "011 relative\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to plot a bearing from a VOR station, a pilot needs to know the magnetic\nvariation:\n",
        "answer": "at the VOR\n",
        "choiceone": "at the aircraft location\n",
        "choicetwo": "at the half-way point between the aircraft and the station\n",
        "choicethree": "at both the VOR and aircraft\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "raft at FL 410 has a DME range of 14 nm. Whatis the ground range from the\nDME?\n",
        "answer": "12.27nm\n",
        "choiceone": "11.68nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "12.85nm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft DME receiver rejects pulses meant for other aircraft because:\n",
        "answer": "The random PRF is unique to each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The transmission and reply frequencies are 63 MHz apart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pulses are transmitted in pairs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the CRT which component is used for brilliance control?\n",
        "answer": "The grid.\n",
        "choiceone": "The cathode.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The anodes.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum range of search radar is dependant on the:\n",
        "answer": "pulse width.\n",
        "choiceone": "radio frequency;\n",
        "choicetwo": "pulse recurrence frequency;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (10).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point C to point A of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "wind direction and velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true heading and groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following defines the type of altitude used when maintaining FL070?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Calibrated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal:\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nistance from A to B = 84 NM.\n\nWhat is the time from A to B?-\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long will it take to fly 5 NM at a groundspeed of 269 Kt ?\n",
        "answer": "1 MIN 07 SEC\n",
        "choiceone": "1 MIN 55 SEC\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 MIN 30 SEC\n",
        "choicethree": "0 MIN 34 SEC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Frequency?\n",
        "answer": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choiceone": "The distance travelled during the transmission in one cycle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international distress frequencies are:\n",
        "answer": "500kHz 121.5MHz 243MHz 8364 kHz\n",
        "choiceone": "500 kHz 121.5kHz 243MHz 8364 MHz\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 MHz 121.5MHz 243 KHZ 8364 MHz\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the VOR indicates TO and the CDI is centered, where will the aircraft always be?\n",
        "answer": "On the reciprocal of the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inbound to the VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the range of the VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Designated operational coverage, transmitter/receiver height, transmission power,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transmission power, transmitter/receiver height, designated operational coverage,\nnight effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transmission power, frequency in use, type of emission, receiver/transmitter height,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "phase comparison;\n",
        "choiceone": "wave transmissions;\n",
        "choicetwo": "limacon positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basic radar operates on:\n",
        "answer": "VHF and higher frequencies;\n",
        "choiceone": "HF and lower frequencies only;\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any frequency in the RF band.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (11).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point A to point B of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "true heading and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "groundspeed and true heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point C to point B of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "groundspeed and true course.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed and heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true heading and groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "istance 300NM|True course 260 degrees, Wind 245 degrees at 45 kts, True\nirspeed 119 kts, Rate of fuel consumption 12.7 gal/hr, What would be the approximate\ngroundspeed and amount of fuel consumed?\n\n",
        "answer": "75 knots; 50.8 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "75 knots; 49.1 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "84 knots; 46.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distance 200 NM,\nTrue course 320 degrees\nWind 215 degrees at 25 kts\nTrue airspeed 116 kts\n",
        "answer": "120 knots; 31.7 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "132 knots; 28.9 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "115 knots; 33.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |Departure path straight out|Takeofftime 1030 2Z|Winds during climb 180\ndegrees at 30 kts, True course during climb 160 degrees, Airport elevation 1,500 ft, True\nairspeed 125 Kts, Rate of climb 500 ftmin, What would be the distance and time upon\nreaching 8,500 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "23 NM and 1044Z\n",
        "choiceone": "20 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 230degrees results in a ground track of 250 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 160 knots results in a groundspeed of 175 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "135 degrees and 59 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "165 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "343 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When planning a distance flight, true course measurements on a Sectional Aeronautical\nChart should be made at a meridian near the midpoint of the course because the\n",
        "answer": "angles formed by lines of longitude and the course line vary from point to point.\n",
        "choiceone": "values of isogonic lines change from point to point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angles formed by isogonic lines and lines of latitude vary from point to point.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Position A is located on the equator at longitude 130\u00b000E.\nPosition B is located 100 NM from A on a bearing of 225\u00b0(T).\nThe coordinates of position B are:\n",
        "answer": "01\u00b011'S 128\u00b049'E\n",
        "choiceone": "01\u00b011'N 131\u00b011\u00b0E\n",
        "choicetwo": "01\u00b011'S 131\u00b011'E\n",
        "choicethree": "01\u00b011'N 128\u00b049'E\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When proceeding, on a given date, along a parallel towards the East, the moment of\nsunrise will occur one hour earlier every 15\u00b0 difference in longitude when it is expressed\nin\n",
        "answer": "UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "LMT\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard Time\n",
        "choicethree": "LAT (local apparent time)\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time difference in Local Mean Time between sunset at positions A (50\u00b0N, 120\u00b0E) and\nB (50\u00b0S, 120\u00b0E) on the 215t of November is:\n",
        "answer": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in B than in A.\n",
        "choiceone": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in A than in B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "negligible small because A and B are located at the same meridian.\n",
        "choicethree": "negligible small because A and B are located symmetrically to the equator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0, variation is 33\u00b0 W and deviation is 3\u00b0E, whatis the True\nHeading?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "229\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "301\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\nWhat is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME (N5150.4 W00829.7) to position\nN5210 W00920?\n",
        "answer": "11\u00b0 - 38NM\n",
        "choiceone": "350\u00b0 - 22NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "295\u00b0 - 38NM\n",
        "choicethree": "170\u00b0 - 22NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent when 100 NM from a DME facility\nand to cross the station at FL120. If the mean GS during the descent is 396 kt, the\nminimum rate of descent required is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1650 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "2400 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1550 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "10.3 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "11.1 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "15.4NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a VOR receiver and two-way commu!\nequipment is required for IFR operation in Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choiceone": "DME and an operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standby communications receiver, DME, and coded transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation 'E\"\ncorrespond?\n",
        "answer": "8 and 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The F layer of the ionosphere is called the:\n",
        "answer": "Appleton layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Kennelly-Heaviside layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gauss layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft leaves NDB ABC, track 075(M), drift 6 left. NDB XYZ bears 235 relative. What\nbearings from both NDBs would be shown on the RMI?\n",
        "answer": "255 & 316\n",
        "choiceone": "261 & 316\n",
        "choicetwo": "255 & 136\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The DME indication when an aircraft is overhead a VOR/DME station at 6000\u2019 is :-\n",
        "answer": "inm\n",
        "choiceone": "Onm\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.3nm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A particular VOR station is undergoing routine maintenance. This is confirmed by.\n",
        "answer": "the removal of the identification signal.\n",
        "choiceone": "transmitting a series of dots after each identification signal;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the removal of the navigational feature;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft passes overhead a DME station at 12000 feet above the station. At that time,\nthe DME reading will be:\n",
        "answer": "approximately 2 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FLAGIOFF, the aircraft is within the cone of silence.\n",
        "choicethree": "fluctuating and not significant.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An echo on a CRT registers a time interval of 280 s (ignoring fly back) out and return.\nDetermine the range of the target.\n",
        "answer": "22.68 nm\n",
        "choiceone": "45.36 nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "26.04 nm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the CRT which component achieves focusing control?\n",
        "answer": "The anodes.\n",
        "choiceone": "The grid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The X plates.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft using a SSR transponder will transmit an IDENT pulse :-\n",
        "answer": "when changing codes,\n",
        "choiceone": "when requested by ATC only,\n",
        "choicetwo": "on initial contact with ATC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant course width:\n",
        "answer": "Will indicate distance from the centre line regardless of distance from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decreases as the VORTAC is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Is provided in approach mode.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (12).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 150 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 8\nmiles off course. If 160 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "6 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 135 degrees results in a ground track of 130 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 135 knots results in a groundspeed of 140 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "246 degrees and 13 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "019 degrees and 12 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 degreesand 13 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "istance 300NM|True course 260 degrees, Wind 245 degrees at 45 kts, True\nirspeed 119 kts, Rate of fuel consumption 12.7 gal/hr, What would be the approximate\ngroundspeed and amount of fuel consumed?\n\n",
        "answer": "75 knots; 50.8 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "75 knots; 49.1 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "84 knots; 46.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Departure path straight out|Takeoff time 1435Z|Winds during climb 175 degrees at 25\nkts, True course during climb 155 degrees Airport elevation 2,000 ft|True ai\nkts|Rate of climb 500 fmin|What would be the distance and time upon react\nfeet MSL?\n\n",
        "answer": "21 NM and 1447Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "27 NM and 1455Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 NM and 1452Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point A to point B of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "true heading and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "groundspeed and true heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many small circles can be drawn between any two points on a sphere?\n",
        "answer": "An unlimited number.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One.\n",
        "choicethree": "Two.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Position A is located on the equator at longitude 130\u00b000E.\nPosition B is located 100 NM from A on a bearing of 225\u00b0(T).\nThe coordinates of position B are:\n",
        "answer": "01\u00b011'S 128\u00b049'E\n",
        "choiceone": "01\u00b011'N 131\u00b011\u00b0E\n",
        "choicetwo": "01\u00b011'S 131\u00b011'E\n",
        "choicethree": "01\u00b011'N 128\u00b049'E\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time difference in Local Mean Time between sunset at positions A (50\u00b0N, 120\u00b0E) and\nB (50\u00b0S, 120\u00b0E) on the 215t of November is:\n",
        "answer": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in B than in A.\n",
        "choiceone": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in A than in B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "negligible small because A and B are located at the same meridian.\n",
        "choicethree": "negligible small because A and B are located symmetrically to the equator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0, variation is 33\u00b0 W and deviation is 3\u00b0E, whatis the True\nHeading?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "229\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "301\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at latitude 10\u00b0 South flies north at a GS of 890 km/h.\n\nWhat will its latitude be after 1.5 hour?\n",
        "answer": "02\u00b000'N\n",
        "choiceone": "12\u00b015'N\n",
        "choicetwo": "22\u00b000'N\n",
        "choicethree": "03\u00b050'N\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1023 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "11.1NM\n",
        "choiceone": "10.3 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "16.6 NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent when 100 NM from a DME facility\nand to cross the station at FL120. If the mean GS during the descent is 396 kt, the\nminimum rate of descent required is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1650 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "2400 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1550 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The True course in the flight log is 270\u00b0, the forecast wind is 045\u00b0(T)/15kt and the TAS is\n\n120kt.\nAfter 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM South of the\n\nintended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position.\nThe track angle error (TKE) is:\n",
        "answer": "5\u00b0L\n",
        "choiceone": "6R\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\u00b0L\n",
        "choicethree": "SR\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 139.) What is the lateral displacement in degrees from the desired ra\non the No. 2NAV?\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With frequency modulated transmissions the:\n",
        "answer": "amplitude is constant and the frequency varies;\n",
        "choiceone": "frequency is constant and the amplitude varies;\n",
        "choicetwo": "amplitude and frequency vary.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 95.) What is the lateral displacement in degrees from the desired radial\non the No. 2 NAV?\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is heading away from an NDB on a track of 035(M), drift 8 right. Another NDB\nbears 115 relative. Give the RMll indications of both NDBs.\n",
        "answer": "142\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "027\u00b08&152*\n",
        "choicetwo": "& 035\"\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a radio wave crosses the coast, leaves the land or passes over the sea the speed\nincreases. When this happens:\n",
        "answer": "The wavelength changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "The frequency changes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No change in either.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ite information from separate\nsources on one dial, namely:\n",
        "answer": "the aircraft heading from a remote-reading compass, bearings from VOR facilities\nand bearings from NDB facilities;\n",
        "choiceone": "only bearings from VOR and NDB facilities;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the true heading from a remote-reading compass, bearings from a VOR facility and a\nbearing from an NDB facility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TVOR is a\n",
        "answer": "VOR with a limited range used in the terminal area.\n",
        "choiceone": "test VOR transmitting such a signal that the reference- and variable signal are always\nin phase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "high power VOR in the frequency range 108 MHz - 112 MHz.\n",
        "choicethree": "low power DVOR in the frequency range 112 MHz - 118 MHz.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the middle marker the indications are:\n",
        "answer": "A flashing amber light with medium pitched dots and dashes.\n",
        "choiceone": "A flashing blue light with low pitched dashes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A flashing white light with very high pitched dots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft will not accept replies from its own transmissions that are reflected from the\n\nground because the :-\n",
        "answer": "interrogation and reply frequencies are 63 Mhz apart,\n",
        "choiceone": "random PRF which is unique to each transmitter,\n",
        "choicetwo": "pulses are transmitted in pairs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distortion due to the effect of beam width on the picture causes:\n",
        "answer": "Addition of one half of the beamwidth distance on either side of the object.\n",
        "choiceone": "Receiver gain being reduced after transmission of the pulse.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two targets to appear as one larger target\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The GPS Control Segment :-\n",
        "answer": "accurately tracks the GPS satellites and provides them with periodic updates\ncorrecting their ephemeris co-ordinates and their clock bias factors.\n",
        "choiceone": "selects the four best satellites to use for navigation with respect to their geometry\nand altitude,\n",
        "choicetwo": "calculates and controls the clock bias error of the aeroplanes receiver,\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (13).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 238 degrees\nVariation 3 degrees W\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\n\nAmbient temperature -15 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 8,500 ft|Forecast wind 160 degrees at 25 kts|Under these\n",
        "answer": "233 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "224 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "241degrees and 178 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 258 degrees, Variation10 degrees E\nIndicated airspeed 142 kts\n\nAmbient temperature +05 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 6,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "270 degrees and 157 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "280 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 350 degrees results in a ground track of 335degrees and a true\nairspeed of 140 knots results in a groundspeed of 115 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "035 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "015 degrees and 30 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "290 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point A to point B of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "true heading and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "groundspeed and true heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 150 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 8\nmiles off course. If 160 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "6 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view Annex 061-600199)\nWhich figure in the Appendix represents the geographic latitude of position P, which is\nsituated above the surface of the ellipsoid?\n\n",
        "answer": "figure A\n",
        "choiceone": "figure B\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure C\n",
        "choicethree": "figure D\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Cor\nthe:\n\nchart earth convergency is most accurately represented at\n",
        "answer": "parallel of origin\n",
        "choiceone": "north and south limits of the chart\n",
        "choicetwo": "standard parallels\n",
        "choicethree": "Equator\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n\nCRK VOR N5150.4 W00829.7,\n\nAircraft position N5220 W00910\n\nWhich of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position?\n\n",
        "answer": "SHA 214\u00b0\nCRK 330\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 025\u00b0\nCRK 141\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 205\u00b0\nCRK 321\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 033\u00b0\nCRK 149\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nPosition NDB (55\u00b010\u00b0N, 012\u00b055'E)\n\nDR Position (54\u00b053\u00b0N, 009\u00b058'E)\n\nNDB on the RMI reads 090\u00b0\n\nMagnetic variation = 10\u00b0W\n\nThe position line has to be plotted on a Lamberts conformal chart with standard\nparallels at 40\u00b0N and 48\u00b0N. Calculate the direction (T) of the bearing to be plotted from\nthe NDB.\n\n",
        "answer": "262\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "272\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "258\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "265\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR (N5243.3 W00853.1) radial 205\u00b0,\nCRK VOR (N5150.4 W00829.7) radial 317\u00b0.\nWhat is the aircraft position?\n",
        "answer": "N5210 W00910\n",
        "choiceone": "N5118 W00913\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5205 wo0915\n",
        "choicethree": "N5215 W00917\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nistance from A to B = 84 NM.\n\nWhat is the time from A to B?-\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nTAS = 135 kt,\n\nHDG (\u00b0T) = 278,\n\nWIV = 140/20kt\n\nCalculate the Track (\u00b0T) and GS?\n",
        "answer": "283 - 150 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "279 - 152 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "272 - 121 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "275 - 150 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is descending down a 6% slope whilst maintaining a GS of 300 kt.\nThe rate of descent of the aircraft is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1800 fumin\n",
        "choiceone": "10800 ftmin\n",
        "choicetwo": "3600 fmin\n",
        "choicethree": "900 fmin\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1023 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "11.1NM\n",
        "choiceone": "10.3 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "16.6 NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-9438A)\nComplete line 2 of the \"FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u2019, positions 'C' to 'D'.\n\nWhat is the HDG*(M) and ETA?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1239 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 188\u00b0 - ETA 1229 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1249 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 183\u00b0 - ETA 1159 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum permissible variation between the two bearing indicators ona\ndual VOR system when checking one VOR against the other?\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees on the ground and in flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 degrees on the ground and in flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees in flight and 4 degrees on the ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 96 and 97.)\nTo which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation 'E' correspond?\n",
        "answer": "8 and 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 41.) If on a magnetic heading of 240 degrees and receiving ADF\nindication 2, what would be the magnetic bearing to the station?\n",
        "answer": "240 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "360 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static interference increases with an:\n",
        "answer": "decrease in frequency;\n",
        "choiceone": "increase in frequency;\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease in wave length.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you understand by the expresion \"phase of an alternating current\u201d\n",
        "answer": "The stage reached in an alternating currents\u2019 cycle at any given instant of time.\n",
        "choiceone": "Particular points in a cycle of two alternating currents provided they are at different\nfrequencies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The direction of the magnetic field in an alternating current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical angle of a radio wave:\n",
        "answer": "Varies with the frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "Varies with phase angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Is constant for all frequencies.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the range of the VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Designated operational coverage, transmitter/receiver height, transmission power,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transmission power, transmitter/receiver height, designated operational coverage,\nnight effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transmission power, frequency in use, type of emission, receiver/transmitter height,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft passes overhead a VORTAC at 1413Z maintaining radial 252, heading 244(M),\nTAS 230 Kts, variation 15W. At 14282 the aircraft is 63 nm from the station. The WIV is:\n\n",
        "answer": "110/40\n",
        "choiceone": "080/40\n",
        "choicetwo": "095/40\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR frequency is selected and VOR and DME indications are received on the\nappropriate ins tors. The VOR ident is CPL and the DME CPZ. This indicates that VOR\nand DME transmitters are :-\n\n",
        "answer": "serving the same location and may be plotted after checking the two positions\n",
        "choiceone": "co-located, and the bearing and range can be plotted from the VOR position,\n",
        "choicetwo": "at two independent positions and are not related.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft DME receiver rejects pulses meant for other aircraft because:\n",
        "answer": "The random PRF is unique to each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The transmission and reply frequencies are 63 MHz apart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pulses are transmitted in pairs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "To improve the detection of precipitation area(s) in e.g thunderstorms, in which the top\nof the cloud lies at or slightly above the level of flight,\n",
        "answer": "the tilt setting should be lower when the aircraft climbs to a higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "the tilt setting should be higher when the aircraft climbs to a higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the tilt setting should be higher when the selected range decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the tilt setting should be lower when the selected range increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The minimum range of search radar is dependant on the:\n",
        "answer": "pulse width.\n",
        "choiceone": "radio frequency;\n",
        "choicetwo": "pulse recurrence frequency;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (14).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point C to point A of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "wind direction and velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true heading and groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-2304A)\nThe UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG (Canada) (49\u00b050'N 097\u00b030'W)\n\n",
        "answer": "1413\n",
        "choiceone": "0930\n",
        "choicetwo": "0113\n",
        "choicethree": "2230\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue Track 300\u00b0\nDrift 8\u00b0R:\nVariation 10\u00b0W\nDeviation -4\u00b0\n\nCalculate the compass heading.\n",
        "answer": "306'\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "294\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "278\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nTAS = 135 kt,\n\nHDG (\u00b0T) = 278,\n\nWIV = 140/20kt\n\nCalculate the Track (\u00b0T) and GS?\n",
        "answer": "283 - 150 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "279 - 152 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "272 - 121 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "275 - 150 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nTAS = 90 kt,\n\nHDG (T) = 355\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 120/20Kt.\n\nCalculate the Track (\u00b0T) and GS?\n",
        "answer": "346 - 102 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "006 - 95 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "358 - 101 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "359 - 102 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue altitude 9000 FT,\nOAT -32\u00b0C,\n\nCAS 200 kt.\n\nWhat is the TAS?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "215 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "210 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Frequency?\n",
        "answer": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choiceone": "The distance travelled during the transmission in one cycle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the range of the VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Designated operational coverage, transmitter/receiver height, transmission power,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transmission power, transmitter/receiver height, designated operational coverage,\nnight effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transmission power, frequency in use, type of emission, receiver/transmitter height,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the VOR indicates TO and the CDI is centered, where will the aircraft always be?\n",
        "answer": "On the reciprocal of the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inbound to the VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "phase comparison;\n",
        "choiceone": "wave transmissions;\n",
        "choicetwo": "limacon positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (15).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How far will an aircraft travel in 3-1/2 minutes if its groundspeed is 165 knots?\n",
        "answer": "9.6 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.8 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12.8 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following defines the type of altitude used when maintaining FL070?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Calibrated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal:\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the chart distance between longitudes 179\u00b0E and 175\u00b0W on a direct Mercator\nchart with a scale of 1: 5 000 000 at the equator?\n",
        "answer": "133 mm\n",
        "choiceone": "106 mm\n",
        "choicetwo": "167mm\n",
        "choicethree": "72mm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nistance from A to B = 84 NM.\n\nWhat is the time from A to B?-\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nRunway direction 305\u00b0(M),\nSurface WIV 260\u00b0(M)/30 Kt.\n\nCalculate the cross-wind component?\n",
        "answer": "21 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "24 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "27 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "18 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue altitude 9000 FT,\nOAT -32\u00b0C,\n\nCAS 200 kt.\n\nWhat is the TAS?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "215 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "210 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a VOR receiver and two-way commu!\nequipment is required for IFR operation in Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choiceone": "DME and an operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standby communications receiver, DME, and coded transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Wave length?\n",
        "answer": "The distance travelled during the transmission of one cycle.\n",
        "choiceone": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the VOR indicates TO and the CDI is centered, where will the aircraft always be?\n",
        "answer": "On the reciprocal of the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inbound to the VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "phase comparison;\n",
        "choiceone": "wave transmissions;\n",
        "choicetwo": "limacon positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basic radar operates on:\n",
        "answer": "VHF and higher frequencies;\n",
        "choiceone": "HF and lower frequencies only;\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any frequency in the RF band.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (16).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following defines the type of altitude used when maintaining FL070?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Calibrated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distance 200 NM,\nTrue course 320 degrees\nWind 215 degrees at 25 kts\nTrue airspeed 116 kts\n",
        "answer": "120 knots; 31.7 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "132 knots; 28.9 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "115 knots; 33.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-2304A)\nThe UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG (Canada) (49\u00b050'N 097\u00b030'W)\n\n",
        "answer": "1413\n",
        "choiceone": "0930\n",
        "choicetwo": "0113\n",
        "choicethree": "2230\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue Track 300\u00b0\nDrift 8\u00b0R:\nVariation 10\u00b0W\nDeviation -4\u00b0\n\nCalculate the compass heading.\n",
        "answer": "306'\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "294\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "278\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nRunway direction 305\u00b0(M),\nSurface WIV 260\u00b0(M)/30 Kt.\n\nCalculate the cross-wind component?\n",
        "answer": "21 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "24 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "27 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "18 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a VOR receiver and two-way commu!\nequipment is required for IFR operation in Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choiceone": "DME and an operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standby communications receiver, DME, and coded transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Frequency?\n",
        "answer": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choiceone": "The distance travelled during the transmission in one cycle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the range of the VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Designated operational coverage, transmitter/receiver height, transmission power,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transmission power, transmitter/receiver height, designated operational coverage,\nnight effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transmission power, frequency in use, type of emission, receiver/transmitter height,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basic radar operates on:\n",
        "answer": "VHF and higher frequencies;\n",
        "choiceone": "HF and lower frequencies only;\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any frequency in the RF band.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (17).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "istance 300NM|True course 260 degrees, Wind 245 degrees at 45 kts, True\nirspeed 119 kts, Rate of fuel consumption 12.7 gal/hr, What would be the approximate\ngroundspeed and amount of fuel consumed?\n\n",
        "answer": "75 knots; 50.8 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "75 knots; 49.1 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "84 knots; 46.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 135 degrees results in a ground track of 130 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 135 knots results in a groundspeed of 140 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "246 degrees and 13 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "019 degrees and 12 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 degreesand 13 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 230degrees results in a ground track of 250 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 160 knots results in a groundspeed of 175 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "135 degrees and 59 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "165 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "343 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 350 degrees results in a ground track of 335degrees and a true\nairspeed of 140 knots results in a groundspeed of 115 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "035 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "015 degrees and 30 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "290 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 258 degrees, Variation10 degrees E\nIndicated airspeed 142 kts\n\nAmbient temperature +05 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 6,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "270 degrees and 157 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "280 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |Departure path straight out|Takeofftime 1030 2Z|Winds during climb 180\ndegrees at 30 kts, True course during climb 160 degrees, Airport elevation 1,500 ft, True\nairspeed 125 Kts, Rate of climb 500 ftmin, What would be the distance and time upon\nreaching 8,500 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "23 NM and 1044Z\n",
        "choiceone": "20 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point A to point B of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "true heading and airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "groundspeed and true heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How far will an aircraft travel in 3-1/2 minutes if its groundspeed is 165 knots?\n",
        "answer": "9.6 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.8 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12.8 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When proceeding, on a given date, along a parallel towards the East, the moment of\nsunrise will occur one hour earlier every 15\u00b0 difference in longitude when it is expressed\nin\n",
        "answer": "UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "LMT\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard Time\n",
        "choicethree": "LAT (local apparent time)\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time difference in Local Mean Time between sunset at positions A (50\u00b0N, 120\u00b0E) and\nB (50\u00b0S, 120\u00b0E) on the 215t of November is:\n",
        "answer": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in B than in A.\n",
        "choiceone": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in A than in B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "negligible small because A and B are located at the same meridian.\n",
        "choicethree": "negligible small because A and B are located symmetrically to the equator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-2304A)\nThe UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG (Canada) (49\u00b050'N 097\u00b030'W)\n\n",
        "answer": "1413\n",
        "choiceone": "0930\n",
        "choicetwo": "0113\n",
        "choicethree": "2230\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n\nCRK VOR N5150.4 W00829.7,\n\nAircraft position N5220 W00910\n\nWhich of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position?\n\n",
        "answer": "SHA 214\u00b0\nCRK 330\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 025\u00b0\nCRK 141\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 205\u00b0\nCRK 321\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 033\u00b0\nCRK 149\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nPosition NDB (55\u00b010\u00b0N, 012\u00b055'E)\n\nDR Position (54\u00b053\u00b0N, 009\u00b058'E)\n\nNDB on the RMI reads 090\u00b0\n\nMagnetic variation = 10\u00b0W\n\nThe position line has to be plotted on a Lamberts conformal chart with standard\nparallels at 40\u00b0N and 48\u00b0N. Calculate the direction (T) of the bearing to be plotted from\nthe NDB.\n\n",
        "answer": "262\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "272\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "258\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "265\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nistance from A to B = 84 NM.\n\nWhat is the time from A to B?-\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nAn aircraft is on final approach to runway 32R (322\u00b0);\n\nThe wind velocity reported by the tower is 350/20 kt;\n\nTAS on approach is 95 kt.\n\nIn order to maintain the centre line, the aircraft's heading (\u00b0M) should be:\n",
        "answer": "328\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "316\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "326\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nTAS = 135 kt,\n\nHDG (\u00b0T) = 278,\n\nWIV = 140/20kt\n\nCalculate the Track (\u00b0T) and GS?\n",
        "answer": "283 - 150 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "279 - 152 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "272 - 121 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "275 - 150 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 110.) In which general direction from the VORTAC is the aircraft\nlocated?\n",
        "answer": "Northeast.\n",
        "choiceone": "Southwest.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Northwest.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 134.) What is the final approach fix for the CONVERGING ILS RWY 9R-\napproach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "1,800 feet MSL and glide slope interception.\n",
        "choiceone": "BWINE INT and 3,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "KELEE INT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 95.) What is the lateral displacement of the aircraft in NM from the radial\nselected on the No. 1 NAV?\n",
        "answer": "5.0 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "7.5 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10.0 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which distance is commonly displayed by a DME indicator?\n",
        "answer": "Slant-range distance in nautical miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Slant-range distance in statute miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The distance from the aircraft to a point at the same altitude directly above the\nVORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The F layer of the ionosphere is called the:\n",
        "answer": "Appleton layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Kennelly-Heaviside layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gauss layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of aerial is used to determine the position of the NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Loop aerial and sense aerial.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sense aerial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Loop aerial.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When will the VOR monitor warn the control point and possibly switch off the station\nradiation?\n",
        "answer": "A change in bearing information in excess of 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "A change in bearing information in excess of 10.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A reduction of 15% in bearing information.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is heading 340(M) and is 30 nm from the VOR on a bearing of 142 from the\nVOR. The pilot has selected 146 on the OBS and the TO/FROM indicator shows FROM.\nWhat would the indication be on a 5 dot VOR indicator?\n",
        "answer": "2 dots fly right.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 dots fly left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 dots fly right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018The greatest error between ground\ndistance is :-\n\nstance to the DME station and the indicated\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the DME station.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes at maximum range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes at maximum range.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low altitudes close to the DME station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An echo on a CRT registers a time interval of 280 s (ignoring fly back) out and return.\nDetermine the range of the target.\n",
        "answer": "22.68 nm\n",
        "choiceone": "45.36 nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "26.04 nm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distortion due to the effect of beam width on the picture causes:\n",
        "answer": "Addition of one half of the beamwidth distance on either side of the object.\n",
        "choiceone": "Receiver gain being reduced after transmission of the pulse.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two targets to appear as one larger target\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (18).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 230degrees results in a ground track of 250 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 160 knots results in a groundspeed of 175 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "135 degrees and 59 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "165 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "343 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |Departure path straight out|Takeofftime 1030 2Z|Winds during climb 180\ndegrees at 30 kts, True course during climb 160 degrees, Airport elevation 1,500 ft, True\nairspeed 125 Kts, Rate of climb 500 ftmin, What would be the distance and time upon\nreaching 8,500 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "23 NM and 1044Z\n",
        "choiceone": "20 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 150 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 8\nmiles off course. If 160 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "6 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distance 200 NM,\nTrue course 320 degrees\nWind 215 degrees at 25 kts\nTrue airspeed 116 kts\n",
        "answer": "120 knots; 31.7 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "132 knots; 28.9 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "115 knots; 33.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many small circles can be drawn between any two points on a sphere?\n",
        "answer": "An unlimited number.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One.\n",
        "choicethree": "Two.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When proceeding, on a given date, along a parallel towards the East, the moment of\nsunrise will occur one hour earlier every 15\u00b0 difference in longitude when it is expressed\nin\n",
        "answer": "UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "LMT\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard Time\n",
        "choicethree": "LAT (local apparent time)\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0, variation is 33\u00b0 W and deviation is 3\u00b0E, whatis the True\nHeading?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "229\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "301\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\nWhat is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME (N5150.4 W00829.7) to position\nN5210 W00920?\n",
        "answer": "11\u00b0 - 38NM\n",
        "choiceone": "350\u00b0 - 22NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "295\u00b0 - 38NM\n",
        "choicethree": "170\u00b0 - 22NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nistance from A to B = 84 NM.\n\nWhat is the time from A to B?-\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nTAS = 135 kt,\n\nHDG (\u00b0T) = 278,\n\nWIV = 140/20kt\n\nCalculate the Track (\u00b0T) and GS?\n",
        "answer": "283 - 150 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "279 - 152 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "272 - 121 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "275 - 150 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 45\u00b0 left of the nose and 3 MIN\nlater on a relative bearing of 90\u00b0 left of the nose.\nThe WIV is calm; aircraft GS 180 kt.\n\nWhat is the minimum distance between the aircraft and the ground feature?\n",
        "answer": "9NM\n",
        "choiceone": "12NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "3NM\n",
        "choicethree": "6NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent when 100 NM from a DME facility\nand to cross the station at FL120. If the mean GS during the descent is 396 kt, the\nminimum rate of descent required is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1650 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "2400 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1550 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1023 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "11.1NM\n",
        "choiceone": "10.3 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "16.6 NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-9438A)\nComplete line 2 of the \"FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u2019, positions 'C' to 'D'.\n\nWhat is the HDG*(M) and ETA?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1239 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 188\u00b0 - ETA 1229 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1249 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 183\u00b0 - ETA 1159 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 100.) What is the magnetic bearing TO the station as indicated by\nillustration 4?\n",
        "answer": "055 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "285 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "235degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to instruments\nbearing FROM the station would be\n\ninformation, the magnetic\n",
        "answer": "175 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "255 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "355degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is required equipment for operating an aircraft within Class B\n\nairspace?\n\n",
        "answer": "A 4096 code transponder with automatic pressure altitude reporting equipment.\n",
        "choiceone": "A VOR receiver with DME.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A 4096 code transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 139.) What is the lateral displacement in degrees from the desired ra\non the No. 2NAV?\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 96 and 97.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "5 and 13.\n",
        "choiceone": "11\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 and 11.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 139.) Which OBS selection on the No. 2 NAV would center the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "174\n",
        "choiceone": "166\n",
        "choicetwo": "335\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Wave length?\n",
        "answer": "The distance travelled during the transmission of one cycle.\n",
        "choiceone": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In flight, a pilot can improve the range of his transmission with a VDF operator by:\n",
        "answer": "increasing altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "speaking louder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flying out of clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreasing altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the minimum level (ISA conditions) that an aircraft, at a range of 113 NM, must fly in\norder to contact the tower on RIT for a VDF bearing from an airport sited 169 ft above\nMSL?\n",
        "answer": "FL60\n",
        "choiceone": "FL50\n",
        "choicetwo": "FL80\n",
        "choicethree": "FL100\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view Annex 062-600184)\nAn aircrafts flying on a MH of 210\u00b0. The magnetic variation at the VOR is 5\u00b0W and at the\naircraft 10\u00b0W.\n\nAccording to the HSI shown at the Annex the aircraft is on radial:\n",
        "answer": "025\n",
        "choiceone": "015\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "195\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018The greatest error between ground\ndistance is :-\n\nstance to the DME station and the indicated\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the DME station.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes at maximum range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes at maximum range.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low altitudes close to the DME station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "raft at FL 410 has a DME range of 14 nm. Whatis the ground range from the\nDME?\n",
        "answer": "12.27nm\n",
        "choiceone": "11.68nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "12.85nm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft will not accept replies from its own transmissions that are reflected from the\n\nground because the :-\n",
        "answer": "interrogation and reply frequencies are 63 Mhz apart,\n",
        "choiceone": "random PRF which is unique to each transmitter,\n",
        "choicetwo": "pulses are transmitted in pairs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following is a function of the cosecant beam:\n",
        "answer": "A reduction of power with decreasing range.\n",
        "choiceone": "An iso-echo display.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An increase of power as the range increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (19).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 258 degrees, Variation10 degrees E\nIndicated airspeed 142 kts\n\nAmbient temperature +05 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 6,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "270 degrees and 157 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "280 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distance 200 NM,\nTrue course 320 degrees\nWind 215 degrees at 25 kts\nTrue airspeed 116 kts\n",
        "answer": "120 knots; 31.7 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "132 knots; 28.9 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "115 knots; 33.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 135 degrees results in a ground track of 130 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 135 knots results in a groundspeed of 140 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "246 degrees and 13 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "019 degrees and 12 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 degreesand 13 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Departure path straight out|Takeoff time 1435Z|Winds during climb 175 degrees at 25\nkts, True course during climb 155 degrees Airport elevation 2,000 ft|True ai\nkts|Rate of climb 500 fmin|What would be the distance and time upon react\nfeet MSL?\n\n",
        "answer": "21 NM and 1447Z.\n",
        "choiceone": "27 NM and 1455Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 NM and 1452Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 141 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 11\nmiles off course. If 71 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "14 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 240 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 25\nmiles off course. If 100 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "21degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-2304A)\nThe UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG (Canada) (49\u00b050'N 097\u00b030'W)\n\n",
        "answer": "1413\n",
        "choiceone": "0930\n",
        "choicetwo": "0113\n",
        "choicethree": "2230\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0, variation is 33\u00b0 W and deviation is 3\u00b0E, whatis the True\nHeading?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "229\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "301\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at latitude 10\u00b0 South flies north at a GS of 890 km/h.\n\nWhat will its latitude be after 1.5 hour?\n",
        "answer": "02\u00b000'N\n",
        "choiceone": "12\u00b015'N\n",
        "choicetwo": "22\u00b000'N\n",
        "choicethree": "03\u00b050'N\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n\nCRK VOR N5150.4 W00829.7,\n\nAircraft position N5220 W00910\n\nWhich of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position?\n\n",
        "answer": "SHA 214\u00b0\nCRK 330\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 025\u00b0\nCRK 141\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 205\u00b0\nCRK 321\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 033\u00b0\nCRK 149\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue Track 300\u00b0\nDrift 8\u00b0R:\nVariation 10\u00b0W\nDeviation -4\u00b0\n\nCalculate the compass heading.\n",
        "answer": "306'\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "294\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "278\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue course A to B = 250\u00b0\nstance A to B= 315 NM\nTAS = 450 kt.\n\nWIV = 200\u00b0/60kt.\n\nETD A = 0650 UTC.\n\nWhat is the ETA at B?\n",
        "answer": "0736 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "0730 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "0810 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "0716 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "10.3 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "11.1 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "15.4NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent when 100 NM from a DME facility\nand to cross the station at FL120. If the mean GS during the descent is 396 kt, the\nminimum rate of descent required is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1650 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "2400 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1550 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 139.) Which OBS selection on the No. 2 NAV would center the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "174\n",
        "choiceone": "166\n",
        "choicetwo": "335\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How should the pilot make a VOR receiver check when the aircraft is located on the\ndesignated checkpoint on the airport surface?\n",
        "answer": "Set the OBS on the designated radial. The CDI must center within plus or minus\n4degrees of that radial with a FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Set the OBS on 180 degrees plus or minus 4 degrees; the CDI should center with a\nFROM indication.\n",
        "choicetwo": "With the aircraft headed directly toward the VOR and the OBS set to 000degrees, the\nCDI should center within plus or minus 4degrees of that radial with a TO indication.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component associated with the ILS\nlocalizer group?\n\nidentified by the last two letters of the\n",
        "answer": "Middle compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inner marker.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Outer compass locator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Wave length?\n",
        "answer": "The distance travelled during the transmission of one cycle.\n",
        "choiceone": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you understand by the expresion \"phase of an alternating current\u201d\n",
        "answer": "The stage reached in an alternating currents\u2019 cycle at any given instant of time.\n",
        "choiceone": "Particular points in a cycle of two alternating currents provided they are at different\nfrequencies.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The direction of the magnetic field in an alternating current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band normally associated with an ILS localiser is:\n",
        "answer": "108,1 - 111,95 MHz.\n",
        "choiceone": "108, 0 - 119,0 MHz;\n",
        "choicetwo": "118,0 - 135,975 MHz;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the wavelength of an NDB transmitting on 375 KHz?\n",
        "answer": "800m\n",
        "choiceone": "8000 m\n",
        "choicetwo": "8m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a VOR the full deflection of the deviation needle left or right represents a departure\nfrom the selected radial of:\n",
        "answer": "10 degrees;\n",
        "choiceone": "5 degrees;\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A particular VOR station is undergoing routine maintenance. This is confirmed by.\n",
        "answer": "the removal of the identification signal.\n",
        "choiceone": "transmitting a series of dots after each identification signal;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the removal of the navigational feature;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is established on radial 135 inbound to VOR XYZ. VOR KLM is 120 nm from\nXYZ on radial 225. At 1230B the aircraft receives QDM 270 from KLM. TAS 300 kts and\nzero wind. What is the ETA at KLM if heading is altered at 1230B?\n",
        "answer": "1304\n",
        "choiceone": "1254\n",
        "choicetwo": "1314\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The distance displayed by the DME indicator is :-\n",
        "answer": "Slant range in nautical miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Slant range in statute miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Correct ground range.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant course width:\n",
        "answer": "Will indicate distance from the centre line regardless of distance from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decreases as the VORTAC is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Is provided in approach mode.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (2).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How far will an aircraft travel in 3-1/2 minutes if its groundspeed is 165 knots?\n",
        "answer": "9.6 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.8 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12.8 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When converting from true heading to true course, a pilot should\n",
        "answer": "subtract right wind correction angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "add right wind correction angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "add left deviation correction angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When converting from magnetic course to true course, a pilot should\n",
        "answer": "add easterly variation regardless of heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "add westerly variation regardless of heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "subtract easterly variation when on a heading of 360 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the chart distance between longitudes 179\u00b0E and 175\u00b0W on a direct Mercator\nchart with a scale of 1: 5 000 000 at the equator?\n",
        "answer": "133 mm\n",
        "choiceone": "106 mm\n",
        "choicetwo": "167mm\n",
        "choicethree": "72mm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international distress frequencies are:\n",
        "answer": "500kHz 121.5MHz 243MHz 8364 kHz\n",
        "choiceone": "500 kHz 121.5kHz 243MHz 8364 MHz\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 MHz 121.5MHz 243 KHZ 8364 MHz\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the VOR indicates TO and the CDI is centered, where will the aircraft always be?\n",
        "answer": "On the reciprocal of the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inbound to the VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (20).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 258 degrees, Variation10 degrees E\nIndicated airspeed 142 kts\n\nAmbient temperature +05 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 6,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "270 degrees and 157 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "280 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When converting from magnetic course to true course, a pilot should\n",
        "answer": "add easterly variation regardless of heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "add westerly variation regardless of heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "subtract easterly variation when on a heading of 360 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following defines the type of altitude used when maintaining FL070?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Calibrated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angular difference between true north and magnetic north is\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "magnetic deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compass acceleration error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0, variation is 33\u00b0 W and deviation is 3\u00b0E, whatis the True\nHeading?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "229\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "301\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the chart distance between longitudes 179\u00b0E and 175\u00b0W on a direct Mercator\nchart with a scale of 1: 5 000 000 at the equator?\n",
        "answer": "133 mm\n",
        "choiceone": "106 mm\n",
        "choicetwo": "167mm\n",
        "choicethree": "72mm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nTAS = 135 kt,\n\nHDG (\u00b0T) = 278,\n\nWIV = 140/20kt\n\nCalculate the Track (\u00b0T) and GS?\n",
        "answer": "283 - 150 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "279 - 152 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "272 - 121 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "275 - 150 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a VOR receiver and two-way commu!\nequipment is required for IFR operation in Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choiceone": "DME and an operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standby communications receiver, DME, and coded transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the VOR indicates TO and the CDI is centered, where will the aircraft always be?\n",
        "answer": "On the reciprocal of the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inbound to the VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "phase comparison;\n",
        "choiceone": "wave transmissions;\n",
        "choicetwo": "limacon positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (21).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When converting from magnetic course to true course, a pilot should\n",
        "answer": "add easterly variation regardless of heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "add westerly variation regardless of heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "subtract easterly variation when on a heading of 360 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distance 200 NM,\nTrue course 320 degrees\nWind 215 degrees at 25 kts\nTrue airspeed 116 kts\n",
        "answer": "120 knots; 31.7 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "132 knots; 28.9 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "115 knots; 33.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 350 degrees results in a ground track of 335degrees and a true\nairspeed of 140 knots results in a groundspeed of 115 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "035 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "015 degrees and 30 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "290 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angular difference between true north and magnetic north is\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "magnetic deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compass acceleration error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal:\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long will it take to fly 5 NM at a groundspeed of 269 Kt ?\n",
        "answer": "1 MIN 07 SEC\n",
        "choiceone": "1 MIN 55 SEC\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 MIN 30 SEC\n",
        "choicethree": "0 MIN 34 SEC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue altitude 9000 FT,\nOAT -32\u00b0C,\n\nCAS 200 kt.\n\nWhat is the TAS?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "215 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "210 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a VOR receiver and two-way commu!\nequipment is required for IFR operation in Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choiceone": "DME and an operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standby communications receiver, DME, and coded transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international distress frequencies are:\n",
        "answer": "500kHz 121.5MHz 243MHz 8364 kHz\n",
        "choiceone": "500 kHz 121.5kHz 243MHz 8364 MHz\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 MHz 121.5MHz 243 KHZ 8364 MHz\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Frequency?\n",
        "answer": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choiceone": "The distance travelled during the transmission in one cycle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the range of the VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Designated operational coverage, transmitter/receiver height, transmission power,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transmission power, transmitter/receiver height, designated operational coverage,\nnight effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transmission power, frequency in use, type of emission, receiver/transmitter height,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basic radar operates on:\n",
        "answer": "VHF and higher frequencies;\n",
        "choiceone": "HF and lower frequencies only;\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any frequency in the RF band.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (22).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angular difference between true north and magnetic north is\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "magnetic deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compass acceleration error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distance 200 NM,\nTrue course 320 degrees\nWind 215 degrees at 25 kts\nTrue airspeed 116 kts\n",
        "answer": "120 knots; 31.7 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "132 knots; 28.9 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "115 knots; 33.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When converting from true heading to true course, a pilot should\n",
        "answer": "subtract right wind correction angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "add right wind correction angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "add left deviation correction angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following defines the type of altitude used when maintaining FL070?\n",
        "answer": "Pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Calibrated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many small circles can be drawn between any two points on a sphere?\n",
        "answer": "An unlimited number.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One.\n",
        "choicethree": "Two.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a VOR receiver and two-way commu!\nequipment is required for IFR operation in Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choiceone": "DME and an operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standby communications receiver, DME, and coded transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Frequency?\n",
        "answer": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choiceone": "The distance travelled during the transmission in one cycle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the VOR indicates TO and the CDI is centered, where will the aircraft always be?\n",
        "answer": "On the reciprocal of the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inbound to the VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the range of the VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Designated operational coverage, transmitter/receiver height, transmission power,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transmission power, transmitter/receiver height, designated operational coverage,\nnight effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transmission power, frequency in use, type of emission, receiver/transmitter height,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "phase comparison;\n",
        "choiceone": "wave transmissions;\n",
        "choicetwo": "limacon positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (23).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point C to point A of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "wind direction and velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true heading and groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 350 degrees results in a ground track of 335degrees and a true\nairspeed of 140 knots results in a groundspeed of 115 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "035 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "015 degrees and 30 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "290 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long will it take to fly 5 NM at a groundspeed of 269 Kt ?\n",
        "answer": "1 MIN 07 SEC\n",
        "choiceone": "1 MIN 55 SEC\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 MIN 30 SEC\n",
        "choicethree": "0 MIN 34 SEC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nRunway direction 305\u00b0(M),\nSurface WIV 260\u00b0(M)/30 Kt.\n\nCalculate the cross-wind component?\n",
        "answer": "21 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "24 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "27 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "18 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue altitude 9000 FT,\nOAT -32\u00b0C,\n\nCAS 200 kt.\n\nWhat is the TAS?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "215 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "210 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a VOR receiver and two-way commu!\nequipment is required for IFR operation in Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choiceone": "DME and an operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standby communications receiver, DME, and coded transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Frequency?\n",
        "answer": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choiceone": "The distance travelled during the transmission in one cycle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the range of the VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Designated operational coverage, transmitter/receiver height, transmission power,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transmission power, transmitter/receiver height, designated operational coverage,\nnight effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transmission power, frequency in use, type of emission, receiver/transmitter height,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "phase comparison;\n",
        "choiceone": "wave transmissions;\n",
        "choicetwo": "limacon positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basic radar operates on:\n",
        "answer": "VHF and higher frequencies;\n",
        "choiceone": "HF and lower frequencies only;\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any frequency in the RF band.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (24).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 350 degrees results in a ground track of 335degrees and a true\nairspeed of 140 knots results in a groundspeed of 115 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "035 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "015 degrees and 30 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "290 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When planning a distance flight, true course measurements on a Sectional Aeronautical\nChart should be made at a meridian near the midpoint of the course because the\n",
        "answer": "angles formed by lines of longitude and the course line vary from point to point.\n",
        "choiceone": "values of isogonic lines change from point to point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angles formed by isogonic lines and lines of latitude vary from point to point.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 150 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 8\nmiles off course. If 160 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "6 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 230degrees results in a ground track of 250 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 160 knots results in a groundspeed of 175 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "135 degrees and 59 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "165 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "343 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 135 degrees results in a ground track of 130 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 135 knots results in a groundspeed of 140 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "246 degrees and 13 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "019 degrees and 12 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 degreesand 13 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distance 200 NM,\nTrue course 320 degrees\nWind 215 degrees at 25 kts\nTrue airspeed 116 kts\n",
        "answer": "120 knots; 31.7 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "132 knots; 28.9 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "115 knots; 33.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 238 degrees\nVariation 3 degrees W\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\n\nAmbient temperature -15 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 8,500 ft|Forecast wind 160 degrees at 25 kts|Under these\n",
        "answer": "233 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "224 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "241degrees and 178 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With an increase in magnetic latitude there will be a decrease in the\n",
        "answer": "directive force.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle of dip.\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical component of the Earth's magnetic field.\n",
        "choicethree": "total magnetic force of the Earth's magnetic field.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal:\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0, variation is 33\u00b0 W and deviation is 3\u00b0E, whatis the True\nHeading?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "229\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "301\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines\n",
        "choicetwo": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin\n",
        "choicethree": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You plan to fly from point A (60\u00b0N 010\u00b0E) to point B (60\u00b0N 020\u00b0E).\nThe gyro North of the gyro compass, assumed to be operating perfectly, with no rate\ncorrection device, is aligned with the true North of point A. The constant gyro heading to\nbe followed when starting from A given that the flight time scheduled is 1h30 min\n\nwith a zero wind, is equal to :\n",
        "answer": "076\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "080\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "066\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "085:\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nistance from A to B = 84 NM.\n\nWhat is the time from A to B?-\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue course A to B = 250\u00b0\nstance A to B= 315 NM\nTAS = 450 kt.\n\nWIV = 200\u00b0/60kt.\n\nETD A = 0650 UTC.\n\nWhat is the ETA at B?\n",
        "answer": "0736 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "0730 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "0810 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "0716 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "10.3 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "11.1 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "15.4NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-9438A)\nComplete line 2 of the \"FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u2019, positions 'C' to 'D'.\n\nWhat is the HDG*(M) and ETA?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1239 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 188\u00b0 - ETA 1229 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1249 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 183\u00b0 - ETA 1159 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 41.) If on a magnetic heading of 240 degrees and receiving ADF\nindication 2, what would be the magnetic bearing to the station?\n",
        "answer": "240 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "360 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical angle of a radio wave:\n",
        "answer": "Varies with the frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "Varies with phase angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Is constant for all frequencies.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two radio aids to navigation that may share a common receiving aerial, are:\n",
        "answer": "ADF and Loran C;\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR and ADF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "ILS and ADF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?\n",
        "answer": "As frequency increases, surface attenuation increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "As frequency increases, surface attenuation decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "As frequency increases, ionospheric attenuation increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a radio wave crosses the coast, leaves the land or passes over the sea the speed\nincreases. When this happens:\n",
        "answer": "The wavelength changes.\n",
        "choiceone": "The frequency changes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No change in either.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The RMI indicates magnetic heading. To convert RMI bearings of NDB's and VOR's the\ncorrect combination for application of magnetic variation\n\n",
        "answer": "NDB Aircraft position VOR Beacon position\n",
        "choiceone": "NDB Beacon position VOR Aircraft position\n",
        "choicetwo": "NDB Beacon position VOR Beacon position\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In flight, a pilot can improve the range of his transmission with a VDF operator by:\n",
        "answer": "increasing altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "speaking louder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flying out of clouds.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreasing altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ite information from separate\nsources on one dial, namely:\n",
        "answer": "the aircraft heading from a remote-reading compass, bearings from VOR facilities\nand bearings from NDB facilities;\n",
        "choiceone": "only bearings from VOR and NDB facilities;\n",
        "choicetwo": "the true heading from a remote-reading compass, bearings from a VOR facility and a\nbearing from an NDB facility.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is established on radial 135 inbound to VOR XYZ. VOR KLM is 120 nm from\nXYZ on radial 225. At 1230B the aircraft receives QDM 270 from KLM. TAS 300 kts and\nzero wind. What is the ETA at KLM if heading is altered at 1230B?\n",
        "answer": "1304\n",
        "choiceone": "1254\n",
        "choicetwo": "1314\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The heading rose of an HSI is frozen on 200\u00b0. Lined up on the ILS of runway 25, the\nlocaliser needle will be:\n",
        "answer": "centred\n",
        "choiceone": "left of centre\n",
        "choicetwo": "right of centre\n",
        "choicethree": "centred with the \u2018fail\u2019 flag showing\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of weather radar (ASR) when the aeroplane is on the ground is:\n",
        "answer": "permitted but used with extreme caution;\n",
        "choiceone": "prohibited;\n",
        "choicetwo": "permitted in maintenance area only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Distortion due to the effect of beam width on the picture causes:\n",
        "answer": "Addition of one half of the beamwidth distance on either side of the object.\n",
        "choiceone": "Receiver gain being reduced after transmission of the pulse.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two targets to appear as one larger target\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (25).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When planning a distance flight, true course measurements on a Sectional Aeronautical\nChart should be made at a meridian near the midpoint of the course because the\n",
        "answer": "angles formed by lines of longitude and the course line vary from point to point.\n",
        "choiceone": "values of isogonic lines change from point to point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angles formed by isogonic lines and lines of latitude vary from point to point.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 150 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 8\nmiles off course. If 160 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "6 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 238 degrees\nVariation 3 degrees W\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\n\nAmbient temperature -15 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 8,500 ft|Forecast wind 160 degrees at 25 kts|Under these\n",
        "answer": "233 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "224 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "241degrees and 178 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |Departure path straight out|Takeofftime 1030 2Z|Winds during climb 180\ndegrees at 30 kts, True course during climb 160 degrees, Airport elevation 1,500 ft, True\nairspeed 125 Kts, Rate of climb 500 ftmin, What would be the distance and time upon\nreaching 8,500 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "23 NM and 1044Z\n",
        "choiceone": "20 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 141 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 11\nmiles off course. If 71 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "14 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view Annex 061-600199)\nWhich figure in the Appendix represents the geographic latitude of position P, which is\nsituated above the surface of the ellipsoid?\n\n",
        "answer": "figure A\n",
        "choiceone": "figure B\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure C\n",
        "choicethree": "figure D\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many small circles can be drawn between any two points on a sphere?\n",
        "answer": "An unlimited number.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One.\n",
        "choicethree": "Two.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-2304A)\nThe UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG (Canada) (49\u00b050'N 097\u00b030'W)\n\n",
        "answer": "1413\n",
        "choiceone": "0930\n",
        "choicetwo": "0113\n",
        "choicethree": "2230\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal:\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nPosition NDB (55\u00b010\u00b0N, 012\u00b055'E)\n\nDR Position (54\u00b053\u00b0N, 009\u00b058'E)\n\nNDB on the RMI reads 090\u00b0\n\nMagnetic variation = 10\u00b0W\n\nThe position line has to be plotted on a Lamberts conformal chart with standard\nparallels at 40\u00b0N and 48\u00b0N. Calculate the direction (T) of the bearing to be plotted from\nthe NDB.\n\n",
        "answer": "262\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "272\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "258\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "265\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR (N5243.3 W00853.1) radial 205\u00b0,\nCRK VOR (N5150.4 W00829.7) radial 317\u00b0.\nWhat is the aircraft position?\n",
        "answer": "N5210 W00910\n",
        "choiceone": "N5118 W00913\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5205 wo0915\n",
        "choicethree": "N5215 W00917\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue Track 300\u00b0\nDrift 8\u00b0R:\nVariation 10\u00b0W\nDeviation -4\u00b0\n\nCalculate the compass heading.\n",
        "answer": "306'\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "294\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "278\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nAn aircraft is on final approach to runway 32R (322\u00b0);\n\nThe wind velocity reported by the tower is 350/20 kt;\n\nTAS on approach is 95 kt.\n\nIn order to maintain the centre line, the aircraft's heading (\u00b0M) should be:\n",
        "answer": "328\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "316\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "326\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 45\u00b0 left of the nose and 3 MIN\nlater on a relative bearing of 90\u00b0 left of the nose.\nThe WIV is calm; aircraft GS 180 kt.\n\nWhat is the minimum distance between the aircraft and the ground feature?\n",
        "answer": "9NM\n",
        "choiceone": "12NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "3NM\n",
        "choicethree": "6NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is\n1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt, the head wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is\n\n1000 ftlmin. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this be\nachieved?\n",
        "answer": "10.3 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "11.1 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "15.4NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 42.) At which aircraft position(s) would you receive OMNI indication X?\n",
        "answer": "1 and 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 and 7.\n",
        "choicetwo": "7 only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 111.) In which general direction from the VORTAC is the aircraft\nlocated?\n",
        "answer": "Northwest.\n",
        "choiceone": "Northeast.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Southeast.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 98 and 99.) To which aircraft position does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n",
        "answer": "16\n",
        "choiceone": "10\n",
        "choicetwo": "14\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 96 and 97.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "9 and 6.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 only.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What frequency corresponds to a wavelength of 650 metres?\n",
        "answer": "462 kHz\n",
        "choiceone": "462 Mhz\n",
        "choicetwo": "462 Hz\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ground wave attenuation is the greatest on:\n",
        "answer": "HF\n",
        "choiceone": "MF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VLF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The F layer of the ionosphere:\n",
        "answer": "May split up into two layers.\n",
        "choiceone": "Is less dense than the other layers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Is the lowest layer of the ionosphere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band normally associated with an ILS localiser is:\n",
        "answer": "108,1 - 111,95 MHz.\n",
        "choiceone": "108, 0 - 119,0 MHz;\n",
        "choicetwo": "118,0 - 135,975 MHz;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to minimize the effect of night effect:\n",
        "answer": "Use a more powerful beacon and use bearings well within the surface wave range.\n",
        "choiceone": "Avoid use of the ADF at sunrise and sunset and use a weaker beacon to eliminate\nskywaves.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Select the station nearest to the aircraft and only use the ADF at sunrise and sunset.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a VOR the full deflection of the deviation needle left or right represents a departure\nfrom the selected radial of:\n",
        "answer": "10 degrees;\n",
        "choiceone": "5 degrees;\n",
        "choicetwo": "2,5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The theoretical maximum range of a VOR in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "1,25 times the square root of the transmitter height plus 1,25 times the\nsquare root of the receiver height\n",
        "choiceone": "1,5 times the square root of the transmitter height plus 1,5 times the square\nroot of the receiver height;\n",
        "choicetwo": "1,15 times the square root of the receiver height plus 1,15 times the square\nroot of the transmitter height.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (3).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 141 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 11\nmiles off course. If 71 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "14 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How far will an aircraft travel in 3-1/2 minutes if its groundspeed is 165 knots?\n",
        "answer": "9.6 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.8 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12.8 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 240 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 25\nmiles off course. If 100 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "21degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 238 degrees\nVariation 3 degrees W\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\n\nAmbient temperature -15 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 8,500 ft|Forecast wind 160 degrees at 25 kts|Under these\n",
        "answer": "233 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "224 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "241degrees and 178 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Position A is located on the equator at longitude 130\u00b000E.\nPosition B is located 100 NM from A on a bearing of 225\u00b0(T).\nThe coordinates of position B are:\n",
        "answer": "01\u00b011'S 128\u00b049'E\n",
        "choiceone": "01\u00b011'N 131\u00b011\u00b0E\n",
        "choicetwo": "01\u00b011'S 131\u00b011'E\n",
        "choicethree": "01\u00b011'N 128\u00b049'E\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0, variation is 33\u00b0 W and deviation is 3\u00b0E, whatis the True\nHeading?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "229\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "301\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Cor\nthe:\n\nchart earth convergency is most accurately represented at\n",
        "answer": "parallel of origin\n",
        "choiceone": "north and south limits of the chart\n",
        "choicetwo": "standard parallels\n",
        "choicethree": "Equator\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR (N5243.3 W00853.1) radial 205\u00b0,\nCRK VOR (N5150.4 W00829.7) radial 317\u00b0.\nWhat is the aircraft position?\n",
        "answer": "N5210 W00910\n",
        "choiceone": "N5118 W00913\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5205 wo0915\n",
        "choicethree": "N5215 W00917\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nPosition NDB (55\u00b010\u00b0N, 012\u00b055'E)\n\nDR Position (54\u00b053\u00b0N, 009\u00b058'E)\n\nNDB on the RMI reads 090\u00b0\n\nMagnetic variation = 10\u00b0W\n\nThe position line has to be plotted on a Lamberts conformal chart with standard\nparallels at 40\u00b0N and 48\u00b0N. Calculate the direction (T) of the bearing to be plotted from\nthe NDB.\n\n",
        "answer": "262\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "272\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "258\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "265\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You plan to fly from point A (60\u00b0N 010\u00b0E) to point B (60\u00b0N 020\u00b0E).\nThe gyro North of the gyro compass, assumed to be operating perfectly, with no rate\ncorrection device, is aligned with the true North of point A. The constant gyro heading to\nbe followed when starting from A given that the flight time scheduled is 1h30 min\n\nwith a zero wind, is equal to :\n",
        "answer": "076\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "080\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "066\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "085:\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nAn aircraft is on final approach to runway 32R (322\u00b0);\n\nThe wind velocity reported by the tower is 350/20 kt;\n\nTAS on approach is 95 kt.\n\nIn order to maintain the centre line, the aircraft's heading (\u00b0M) should be:\n",
        "answer": "328\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "316\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "326\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 45\u00b0 left of the nose and 3 MIN\nlater on a relative bearing of 90\u00b0 left of the nose.\nThe WIV is calm; aircraft GS 180 kt.\n\nWhat is the minimum distance between the aircraft and the ground feature?\n",
        "answer": "9NM\n",
        "choiceone": "12NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "3NM\n",
        "choicethree": "6NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is descending down a 6% slope whilst maintaining a GS of 300 kt.\nThe rate of descent of the aircraft is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1800 fumin\n",
        "choiceone": "10800 ftmin\n",
        "choicetwo": "3600 fmin\n",
        "choicethree": "900 fmin\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-9438A)\nComplete line 2 of the \"FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u2019, positions 'C' to 'D'.\n\nWhat is the HDG*(M) and ETA?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1239 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 188\u00b0 - ETA 1229 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1249 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 183\u00b0 - ETA 1159 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component associated with the ILS\nlocalizer group?\n\nidentified by the last two letters of the\n",
        "answer": "Middle compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inner marker.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Outer compass locator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 95.)\nWhich OBS selection on the No. 2 NAV would center the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "174 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "166 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "335 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The F layer of the ionosphere:\n",
        "answer": "May split up into two layers.\n",
        "choiceone": "Is less dense than the other layers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Is the lowest layer of the ionosphere.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ADF reading must be maintained in order to maintain a track of 165(T) away from\nan NDB, variation 16 W and drift 8 port?\n",
        "answer": "172 relative.\n",
        "choiceone": "352 relative\n",
        "choicetwo": "188 relative.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying a constant heading with 8 starboard drift and is making good a track\nparallel to the centreline of an airway but 5 nm off to the left of the centreline. Estimate\nthe ADF reading on an NDB on the centreline but 42 nm ahead.\n",
        "answer": "015 relative\n",
        "choiceone": "359 relative\n",
        "choicetwo": "011 relative\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With an OBS set to 090 and the directional phase lagging the reference phase by 280,\nthe VOR indicator will show:\n",
        "answer": "TO and fly right.\n",
        "choiceone": "FROM and fly right.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TO and fly left.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018The greatest error between ground\ndistance is :-\n\nstance to the DME station and the indicated\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the DME station.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes at maximum range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes at maximum range.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low altitudes close to the DME station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft DME receiver rejects pulses meant for other aircraft because:\n",
        "answer": "The random PRF is unique to each aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "The transmission and reply frequencies are 63 MHz apart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pulses are transmitted in pairs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of masking the DME antenna of the aircraft from the ground installation is that\nInterruption of reception of DME signals results in:\n",
        "answer": "The Airborne installation switching to the memory mode for about 10 to 15 seconds.\n",
        "choiceone": "The ground installation not sending any pulse pairs...\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airborne equipment switching directly to the search mode.\n",
        "choicethree": "The signal controlled search circuit (SCS) blanking the DME display.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft will not accept replies from its own transmissions that are reflected from the\n\nground because the :-\n",
        "answer": "interrogation and reply frequencies are 63 Mhz apart,\n",
        "choiceone": "random PRF which is unique to each transmitter,\n",
        "choicetwo": "pulses are transmitted in pairs.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the CRT which component achieves focusing control?\n",
        "answer": "The anodes.\n",
        "choiceone": "The grid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The X plates.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following is a function of the cosecant beam:\n",
        "answer": "A reduction of power with decreasing range.\n",
        "choiceone": "An iso-echo display.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An increase of power as the range increases.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The airborne SSR transponder reply to a Mode A interrogation is :-\n",
        "answer": "12 pulses transmitted between two framing pulses,\n",
        "choiceone": "two framing pulses 20.3 us apart,\n",
        "choicetwo": "between O and 12 pulses transmitted between two fraiming pulses.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (4).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When converting from true course to magnetic heading, a pilot should\n",
        "answer": "add westerly variation and subtract left wind correction angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "subtract easterly variation and right wind correction angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "subtract westerly variation and add right wind correction angle.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When converting from magnetic course to true course, a pilot should\n",
        "answer": "add easterly variation regardless of heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "add westerly variation regardless of heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "subtract easterly variation when on a heading of 360 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long will it take to fly 5 NM at a groundspeed of 269 Kt ?\n",
        "answer": "1 MIN 07 SEC\n",
        "choiceone": "1 MIN 55 SEC\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 MIN 30 SEC\n",
        "choicethree": "0 MIN 34 SEC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In addition to a VOR receiver and two-way commu!\nequipment is required for IFR operation in Class B airspace?\n",
        "answer": "An operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choiceone": "DME and an operable coded transponder having Mode C capability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standby communications receiver, DME, and coded transponder.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most common source of static i:\n",
        "answer": "Lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Noise.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turbulence\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Wave length?\n",
        "answer": "The distance travelled during the transmission of one cycle.\n",
        "choiceone": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Frequency?\n",
        "answer": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choiceone": "The distance travelled during the transmission in one cycle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The international distress frequencies are:\n",
        "answer": "500kHz 121.5MHz 243MHz 8364 kHz\n",
        "choiceone": "500 kHz 121.5kHz 243MHz 8364 MHz\n",
        "choicetwo": "500 MHz 121.5MHz 243 KHZ 8364 MHz\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 062-9917A)\nWhat wind velocity is indicated?\n",
        "answer": "105\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choiceone": "030\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(M)/20KT\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (5).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point C to point A of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "wind direction and velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true heading and groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 350 degrees results in a ground track of 335degrees and a true\nairspeed of 140 knots results in a groundspeed of 115 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "035 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "015 degrees and 30 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "290 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "lf the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0, variation is 33\u00b0 W and deviation is 3\u00b0E, whatis the True\nHeading?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "229\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "301\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal:\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind velocity.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the chart distance between longitudes 179\u00b0E and 175\u00b0W on a direct Mercator\nchart with a scale of 1: 5 000 000 at the equator?\n",
        "answer": "133 mm\n",
        "choiceone": "106 mm\n",
        "choicetwo": "167mm\n",
        "choicethree": "72mm\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nTAS = 90 kt,\n\nHDG (T) = 355\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 120/20Kt.\n\nCalculate the Track (\u00b0T) and GS?\n",
        "answer": "346 - 102 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "006 - 95 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "358 - 101 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "359 - 102 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nRunway direction 305\u00b0(M),\nSurface WIV 260\u00b0(M)/30 Kt.\n\nCalculate the cross-wind component?\n",
        "answer": "21 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "24 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "27 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "18 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue altitude 9000 FT,\nOAT -32\u00b0C,\n\nCAS 200 kt.\n\nWhat is the TAS?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "215 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "210 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the DMI icator have the greatest error between ground distance to the\nVORTAC and displayed distance?\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the VORTAC.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes far from the VORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figures 140 and 141.) To which aircraft position(s) does HSI presentation\ncorrespond?\n\n",
        "answer": "7 and 11.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 and 13.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What ication should a pilot receive when a VOR station is undergoing maintenance\nand may be considered unreliable?\n",
        "answer": "No coded identification, but possible navigation indications.\n",
        "choiceone": "Coded identification, but no navigation indications.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A voice recording on the VOR frequency announcing that the VOR is out of service\nfor maintenance.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the course deviation indicator (CDI) considered to have a full-scale deflection?\n",
        "answer": "When the CDI deflects from the center of the scale to full-scale left or right.\n",
        "choiceone": "When the CDI deflects from full-scale left to full-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When the CDI deflects from half-scale left to half-scale right, or vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR receiver with normal five-dot course sensitivity shows a three-dot deflection at 30\nNM from the station. The aircraft would be displaced approximately how far from the\ncourse centerline?\n",
        "answer": "3. NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transmission frequency is 85 MHz, whatis the wavelength?\n",
        "answer": "3.53\n\nm\n",
        "choiceone": "2.83\n\nm\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.55m\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "what is Frequency?\n",
        "answer": "The number of cycles per second.\n",
        "choiceone": "The distance travelled during the transmission in one cycle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One complete change of direction of current.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201csquelch\u201d control on a VHF communication receiver:\n",
        "answer": "Disables receiver output when no signals are being received so preventing noise\nbeing fed to crew headsets.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extends the range of the receiver.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Prevents feed-back.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ADF pointer measures a bearing from an NDB relative to:\n",
        "answer": "Aircraft heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "Magnetic north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aircraft track.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the OBS is set to 105 and the CDI centered and TO indicated:\n",
        "answer": "The magnetic track to the station is 105.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft bears 105(M) from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The true track to the station is 105.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR CDI has the OBS set at 090. The variable phase signal lags the reference signal\nby 280. The CDI indication will be:\n",
        "answer": "Needle RIGHT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Needle LEFT with TO indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Needle Right with FROM indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the range of the VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Designated operational coverage, transmitter/receiver height, transmission power,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "choiceone": "Transmission power, transmitter/receiver height, designated operational coverage,\nnight effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transmission power, frequency in use, type of emission, receiver/transmitter height,\nnature of terrain.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the VOR indicates TO and the CDI is centered, where will the aircraft always be?\n",
        "answer": "On the reciprocal of the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inbound to the VOR.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the radial identified on the course selector.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A full scale deflection on a VOR receiver occurs when the aircraft is:\n",
        "answer": "10 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 from the selected course when close to the station and 10 from the selected\ncourse when far from the station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 or more from the selected bearing.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "phase comparison;\n",
        "choiceone": "wave transmissions;\n",
        "choicetwo": "limacon positions.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The factors affecting the accuracy of a VOR reading are:\n",
        "answer": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "airborne equipment; site error; propagation error; refraction error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "airborne equipment; site error; conduction error;propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors would affect the accuracy of a VOR?\n",
        "answer": "Site error, propagation error, airborne equipment error, interference error.\n",
        "choiceone": "Site error, propagation error, night effect, airborne equipment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propagation error, site error, pilotage error, transmitting power.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to the VOR when the\nsetting:\n\ncraft heading agrees approximately with the OBS\n",
        "answer": "Fly towards the CDI regardless of the TO/FROM indication.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly towards the CDI provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly away from the needle provided FROM is indicated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the DME frequency band?\n",
        "answer": "UHF\n",
        "choiceone": "VLF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VHF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Basic radar operates on:\n",
        "answer": "VHF and higher frequencies;\n",
        "choiceone": "HF and lower frequencies only;\n",
        "choicetwo": "Any frequency in the RF band.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The PRF of a radar installation is 570 pps. What is the time interval between successive\ntransmissions of the leading edges of the pulse?\n",
        "answer": "1754.39 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "1140.00 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1643.85 s.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (6).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point C to point B of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "groundspeed and true course.\n",
        "choiceone": "airspeed and heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true heading and groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |True course\n330 degrees\n\nVariation 15 degrees E\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\nAmbient temperature -10 degrees C\nPressure altitude 4,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "323 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "332 degrees and 166 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "340 degrees and 177 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "istance 300NM|True course 260 degrees, Wind 245 degrees at 45 kts, True\nirspeed 119 kts, Rate of fuel consumption 12.7 gal/hr, What would be the approximate\ngroundspeed and amount of fuel consumed?\n\n",
        "answer": "75 knots; 50.8 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "75 knots; 49.1 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "84 knots; 46.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 150 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 8\nmiles off course. If 160 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "6 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "9 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 141 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 11\nmiles off course. If 71 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "14 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 135 degrees results in a ground track of 130 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 135 knots results in a groundspeed of 140 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "246 degrees and 13 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "019 degrees and 12 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 degreesand 13 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |Departure path straight out|Takeofftime 1030 2Z|Winds during climb 180\ndegrees at 30 kts, True course during climb 160 degrees, Airport elevation 1,500 ft, True\nairspeed 125 Kts, Rate of climb 500 ftmin, What would be the distance and time upon\nreaching 8,500 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "23 NM and 1044Z\n",
        "choiceone": "20 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view Annex 061-600199)\nWhich figure in the Appendix represents the geographic latitude of position P, which is\nsituated above the surface of the ellipsoid?\n\n",
        "answer": "figure A\n",
        "choiceone": "figure B\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure C\n",
        "choicethree": "figure D\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many small circles can be drawn between any two points on a sphere?\n",
        "answer": "An unlimited number.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "One.\n",
        "choicethree": "Two.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-2304A)\nThe UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG (Canada) (49\u00b050'N 097\u00b030'W)\n\n",
        "answer": "1413\n",
        "choiceone": "0930\n",
        "choicetwo": "0113\n",
        "choicethree": "2230\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time difference in Local Mean Time between sunset at positions A (50\u00b0N, 120\u00b0E) and\nB (50\u00b0S, 120\u00b0E) on the 215t of November is:\n",
        "answer": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in B than in A.\n",
        "choiceone": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in A than in B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "negligible small because A and B are located at the same meridian.\n",
        "choicethree": "negligible small because A and B are located symmetrically to the equator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "With an increase in magnetic latitude there will be a decrease in the\n",
        "answer": "directive force.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle of dip.\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical component of the Earth's magnetic field.\n",
        "choicethree": "total magnetic force of the Earth's magnetic field.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nPosition NDB (55\u00b010\u00b0N, 012\u00b055'E)\n\nDR Position (54\u00b053\u00b0N, 009\u00b058'E)\n\nNDB on the RMI reads 090\u00b0\n\nMagnetic variation = 10\u00b0W\n\nThe position line has to be plotted on a Lamberts conformal chart with standard\nparallels at 40\u00b0N and 48\u00b0N. Calculate the direction (T) of the bearing to be plotted from\nthe NDB.\n\n",
        "answer": "262\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "272\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "258\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "265\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTAS = 290 Kt,\n\nTrue HDG = 171\u00b0,\n\nWIV = 340\u00b0(T)/30kt\n\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L -314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R -314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nAn aircraft is on final approach to runway 32R (322\u00b0);\n\nThe wind velocity reported by the tower is 350/20 kt;\n\nTAS on approach is 95 kt.\n\nIn order to maintain the centre line, the aircraft's heading (\u00b0M) should be:\n",
        "answer": "328\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "316\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "326\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue altitude 9000 FT,\nOAT -32\u00b0C,\n\nCAS 200 kt.\n\nWhat is the TAS?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "215 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "210 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent when 100 NM from a DME facility\nand to cross the station at FL120. If the mean GS during the descent is 396 kt, the\nminimum rate of descent required is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1650 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "2400 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1550 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which distance is displayed by the DME indicator?\n",
        "answer": "Slant range distance in NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "Slant range distance in SM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line-of-sight direct distance from aircraft to VORTAC in SM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the ATC term \u2018Radar Contact' signify?\n",
        "answer": "Your aircraft has been identified on the radar display and radar flight-following will\nbe provided until radar identification is terminated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Your aircraft has been identified and you will receive separation from all aircraft while\nin contact with this radar facility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "You will be given traffic advisories until advised the service has been terminated or\nthat radar contact has been lost.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 41.) If on a magnetic heading of 240 degrees and receiving ADF\nindication 2, what would be the magnetic bearing to the station?\n",
        "answer": "240 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "180 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "360 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 139.) What is the lateral displacement in degrees from the desired ra\non the No. 2NAV?\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "During day time the ionosphere is split into the following three distinct layers:\n",
        "answer": "D layer, Kennelly-Heaviside layer, Appleton layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "E layer, Appleton layer, F layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "D layer, Kennelly-Heaviside layer, E layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The F layer of the ionosphere is called the:\n",
        "answer": "Appleton layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Kennelly-Heaviside layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gauss layer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is your position with respect to the 060 bearing to the NDB? Heading 050(M), ADF\nindicates 360(R).\n",
        "answer": "Inbound, right of course.\n",
        "choiceone": "Outbound, left of course.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Outbound, right of course.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The inbound track to a NDB is 045(T), variation 10 W, drift 7 right. What relative bearing\nmust be maintained on the ADF to reach the NDB?\n",
        "answer": "0079\n",
        "choiceone": "3530\n",
        "choicetwo": "0009\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft's heading is 070\u00b0 (M) Variation 10\u00b0E . An NDB bears 200 relative. The RMI\nwill indicate:\n",
        "answer": "270.\n",
        "choiceone": "260;\n",
        "choicetwo": "280;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the main VOR transmitter is switched off and a standby trans!\noperation, bearing information may be unreliable and as a warning:\n",
        "answer": "no identification signal is transmitted;\n",
        "choiceone": "identification signals are transmitted together with voice transmission\nwarnings;\n",
        "choicetwo": "a continuous bleep is transmitted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an ident signal\n\nreceived once in 30 seconds on a frequency paired VOR/DME, then\n",
        "answer": "the DME only is operational,\n",
        "choiceone": "the VOR only is operational,\n",
        "choicetwo": "both facilities are operational.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft passes overhead a DME station at 12000 feet above the station. At that time,\nthe DME reading will be:\n",
        "answer": "approximately 2 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FLAGIOFF, the aircraft is within the cone of silence.\n",
        "choicethree": "fluctuating and not significant.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an Airborne Weather Radar that has a colour cathode display increasing severity of\nrain and turbulence is generally shown by a change of colour from:\n",
        "answer": "green to yellow to red\n",
        "choiceone": "yellow to amber to blue\n",
        "choicetwo": "green to red to black\n",
        "choicethree": "yellow to orange to red\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (7).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 141 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 11\nmiles off course. If 71 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "14 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 238 degrees\nVariation 3 degrees W\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\n\nAmbient temperature -15 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 8,500 ft|Forecast wind 160 degrees at 25 kts|Under these\n",
        "answer": "233 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "224 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "241degrees and 178 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "How far will an aircraft travel in 3-1/2 minutes if its groundspeed is 165 knots?\n",
        "answer": "9.6 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "5.8 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "12.8 NM.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 258 degrees, Variation10 degrees E\nIndicated airspeed 142 kts\n\nAmbient temperature +05 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 6,500 ft\n",
        "answer": "260 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "270 degrees and 157 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "280 degrees and 155 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "istance 300NM|True course 260 degrees, Wind 245 degrees at 45 kts, True\nirspeed 119 kts, Rate of fuel consumption 12.7 gal/hr, What would be the approximate\ngroundspeed and amount of fuel consumed?\n\n",
        "answer": "75 knots; 50.8 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "75 knots; 49.1 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "84 knots; 46.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about longitude and latitude is true?\n",
        "answer": "Lines of longitude cross the Equator at right angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lines of longitude are parallel to the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The 0 degrees line of latitude passes through Greenwich, England.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When proceeding, on a given date, along a parallel towards the East, the moment of\nsunrise will occur one hour earlier every 15\u00b0 difference in longitude when it is expressed\nin\n",
        "answer": "UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "LMT\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard Time\n",
        "choicethree": "LAT (local apparent time)\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at latitude 10\u00b0 South flies north at a GS of 890 km/h.\n\nWhat will its latitude be after 1.5 hour?\n",
        "answer": "02\u00b000'N\n",
        "choiceone": "12\u00b015'N\n",
        "choicetwo": "22\u00b000'N\n",
        "choicethree": "03\u00b050'N\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Cor\nthe:\n\nchart earth convergency is most accurately represented at\n",
        "answer": "parallel of origin\n",
        "choiceone": "north and south limits of the chart\n",
        "choicetwo": "standard parallels\n",
        "choicethree": "Equator\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "You plan to fly from point A (60\u00b0N 010\u00b0E) to point B (60\u00b0N 020\u00b0E).\nThe gyro North of the gyro compass, assumed to be operating perfectly, with no rate\ncorrection device, is aligned with the true North of point A. The constant gyro heading to\nbe followed when starting from A given that the flight time scheduled is 1h30 min\n\nwith a zero wind, is equal to :\n",
        "answer": "076\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "080\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "066\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "085:\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue course A to B = 250\u00b0\nstance A to B= 315 NM\nTAS = 450 kt.\n\nWIV = 200\u00b0/60kt.\n\nETD A = 0650 UTC.\n\nWhat is the ETA at B?\n",
        "answer": "0736 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "0730 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "0810 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "0716 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nistance from A to B = 84 NM.\n\nWhat is the time from A to B?-\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\nAn aircraft is on final approach to runway 32R (322\u00b0);\n\nThe wind velocity reported by the tower is 350/20 kt;\n\nTAS on approach is 95 kt.\n\nIn order to maintain the centre line, the aircraft's heading (\u00b0M) should be:\n",
        "answer": "328\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "316\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "326\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ni:\n\nTrue Track = 095\u00b0,\nTAS = 160 kt,\n\nTrue Heading = 087\u00b0,\nGS = 130 kts;\nCalculate WIV\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 45\u00b0 left of the nose and 3 MIN\nlater on a relative bearing of 90\u00b0 left of the nose.\nThe WIV is calm; aircraft GS 180 kt.\n\nWhat is the minimum distance between the aircraft and the ground feature?\n",
        "answer": "9NM\n",
        "choiceone": "12NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "3NM\n",
        "choicethree": "6NM\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which distance is commonly displayed by a DME indicator?\n",
        "answer": "Slant-range distance in nautical miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Slant-range distance in statute miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The distance from the aircraft to a point at the same altitude directly above the\nVORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum permissible variation between the two bearing indicators ona\ndual VOR system when checking one VOR against the other?\n",
        "answer": "4 degrees on the ground and in flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "6 degrees on the ground and in flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 degrees in flight and 4 degrees on the ground.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component associated with the ILS\nlocalizer identification group?\n\nidentified by the first two letters of the\n",
        "answer": "Outer compass locator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inner marker.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Middle compass locator.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following should be considered as station passage when using VOR?\n",
        "answer": "The first complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first flickering of the TO-FROM indicator and CDI as the station is approached.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The first full-scale deflection of the CDI.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a 1/2 scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "Sdegrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ionospheric density of the E layer is greatest at:\n",
        "answer": "Midday in summer.\n",
        "choiceone": "Midday in winter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Midnight in summer.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ground wave attenuation is the greatest on:\n",
        "answer": "HF\n",
        "choiceone": "MF\n",
        "choicetwo": "VLF\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "No. 1 pointer of a RMlis tuned to a VOR and no. 2 pointer is tuned to a co-located NDB.\nThe pointers will:\n",
        "answer": "Point in different directions due to, the difference in variation between the aircraft\nand the station.\n",
        "choiceone": "Point in the same direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point in different directions because the VOR uses VHF and the NDB uses LF/MF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "From where can ATIS information be received?\n",
        "answer": "At certain times from airfield VORs.\n",
        "choiceone": "From an ILS transmission.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At all times from any VOR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The two modulations from which bearing information for the VOR is obtained are:\n",
        "answer": "Reference signal frequency modulated and directional signal apparent amplitude\nmodulated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Both frequency modulated at the transmitter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reference signal apparent amplitude modulated and directional signal frequency\nmodulated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After passing overhead a VOR the CDI shows a scale deviation to the right. What is\nindicated if the deflection remains constant for a period of time?\n",
        "answer": "The aircraft is flying further from the radial.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aircraft is flying closer to the radial.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The OBS is erroneously set on the reciprocal heading.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of operation of a VOR is bearing measurement by:\n",
        "answer": "Phase comparison.\n",
        "choiceone": "Polarisation comparison.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Modulation measurement.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "TVOR is a\n",
        "answer": "VOR with a limited range used in the terminal area.\n",
        "choiceone": "test VOR transmitting such a signal that the reference- and variable signal are always\nin phase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "high power VOR in the frequency range 108 MHz - 112 MHz.\n",
        "choicethree": "low power DVOR in the frequency range 112 MHz - 118 MHz.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the main VOR transmitter is switched off and a standby trans!\noperation, bearing information may be unreliable and as a warning:\n",
        "answer": "no identification signal is transmitted;\n",
        "choiceone": "identification signals are transmitted together with voice transmission\nwarnings;\n",
        "choicetwo": "a continuous bleep is transmitted.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u2018The greatest error between ground\ndistance is :-\n\nstance to the DME station and the indicated\n",
        "answer": "High altitudes close to the DME station.\n",
        "choiceone": "High altitudes at maximum range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low altitudes at maximum range.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low altitudes close to the DME station.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft passes overhead a DME station at 12000 feet above the station. At that time,\nthe DME reading will be:\n",
        "answer": "approximately 2 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "0 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "FLAGIOFF, the aircraft is within the cone of silence.\n",
        "choicethree": "fluctuating and not significant.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (8).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "ion will true altitude be lower than indicated altitude with an altimeter\nHg?\n\nUnder what cont\nsetting of 29.92\"\n",
        "answer": "In colder than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "In warmer than standard air temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When density altitude is higher than indicated altitude.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "After 141 miles are flown from the departure point, the aircraft's position is located 11\nmiles off course. If 71 miles remain to be flown, what approximate total correction\nshould be made to converge on the destination?\n",
        "answer": "14 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "8 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "11 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 40.) The line from point C to point A of the wind triangle represents\n",
        "answer": "wind direction and velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "true course and groundspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true heading and groundspeed.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 230degrees results in a ground track of 250 degrees and a true\nairspeed of 160 knots results in a groundspeed of 175 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "135 degrees and 59 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "165 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "343 degrees and 60 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "istance 300NM|True course 260 degrees, Wind 245 degrees at 45 kts, True\nirspeed 119 kts, Rate of fuel consumption 12.7 gal/hr, What would be the approximate\ngroundspeed and amount of fuel consumed?\n\n",
        "answer": "75 knots; 50.8 gallons.\n",
        "choiceone": "75 knots; 49.1 gallons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "84 knots; 46.1 gallons.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "GIVEN: |Departure path straight out|Takeofftime 1030 2Z|Winds during climb 180\ndegrees at 30 kts, True course during climb 160 degrees, Airport elevation 1,500 ft, True\nairspeed 125 Kts, Rate of climb 500 ftmin, What would be the distance and time upon\nreaching 8,500 feet MSL?\n",
        "answer": "23 NM and 1044Z\n",
        "choiceone": "20 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "choicetwo": "25 NM and 1047Z.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "True course 238 degrees\nVariation 3 degrees W\n\nIndicated airspeed 160 kts\n\nAmbient temperature -15 degrees C\n\nPressure altitude 8,500 ft|Forecast wind 160 degrees at 25 kts|Under these\n",
        "answer": "233 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "224 degrees and 171 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "241degrees and 178 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a true heading of 350 degrees results in a ground track of 335degrees and a true\nairspeed of 140 knots results in a groundspeed of 115 knots, the wind would be from\n",
        "answer": "035 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "choiceone": "015 degrees and 30 knots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "290 degrees and 40 knots.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When proceeding, on a given date, along a parallel towards the East, the moment of\nsunrise will occur one hour earlier every 15\u00b0 difference in longitude when it is expressed\nin\n",
        "answer": "UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "LMT\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard Time\n",
        "choicethree": "LAT (local apparent time)\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-2304A)\nThe UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG (Canada) (49\u00b050'N 097\u00b030'W)\n\n",
        "answer": "1413\n",
        "choiceone": "0930\n",
        "choicetwo": "0113\n",
        "choicethree": "2230\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1: 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm, the\ndistance from A to B in NM is:\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "38\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "70.4\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Cor\nthe:\n\nchart earth convergency is most accurately represented at\n",
        "answer": "parallel of origin\n",
        "choiceone": "north and south limits of the chart\n",
        "choicetwo": "standard parallels\n",
        "choicethree": "Equator\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A)\n\nGiven:\n\nSHA VOR (N5243.3 W00853.1) radial 205\u00b0,\nCRK VOR (N5150.4 W00829.7) radial 317\u00b0.\nWhat is the aircraft position?\n",
        "answer": "N5210 W00910\n",
        "choiceone": "N5118 W00913\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5205 wo0915\n",
        "choicethree": "N5215 W00917\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue Track 300\u00b0\nDrift 8\u00b0R:\nVariation 10\u00b0W\nDeviation -4\u00b0\n\nCalculate the compass heading.\n",
        "answer": "306'\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "294\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "278\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n\nTrue altitude 9000 FT,\nOAT -32\u00b0C,\n\nCAS 200 kt.\n\nWhat is the TAS?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "215 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "210 kt\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The True course in the flight log is 270\u00b0, the forecast wind is 045\u00b0(T)/15kt and the TAS is\n\n120kt.\nAfter 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM South of the\n\nintended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position.\nThe track angle error (TKE) is:\n",
        "answer": "5\u00b0L\n",
        "choiceone": "6R\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\u00b0L\n",
        "choicethree": "SR\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u2018A\u2019 to position 'B\u2019, distance 320 NM, at an\naverage GS of 180 kt It departs \u2018A\u2019 at 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u2018\nthe aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\n\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at'B'?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "What angular deviation from a VOR course centerline is represented by a full-scale\ndeflection of the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "10degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "4degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which distance is commonly displayed by a DME indicator?\n",
        "answer": "Slant-range distance in nautical miles.\n",
        "choiceone": "Slant-range distance in statute miles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The distance from the aircraft to a point at the same altitude directly above the\nVORTAC.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a VORIDME is collocated under frequency pairings and the VOR portion is\ninoperative, the DME identifier will repeat at an interval of\n",
        "answer": "30 second intervals at 1350 Hz.\n",
        "choiceone": "20 second intervals at 1020 Hz.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 second intervals at 1350 Hz.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 95.)\nWhich OBS selection on the No. 2 NAV would center the CDI?\n",
        "answer": "174 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "166 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "335 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "When using VOR for navigation, which of the following should be con:\npassage?\n",
        "answer": "The first positive, complete reversal of the TO-FROM indicator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The first movement of the CDI as the airplane enters the zone of confusion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The moment the TO-FROM indicator becomes blank.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Refer to Figure 134.) What is the final approach fix for the CONVERGING ILS RWY 9R-\napproach procedure?\n",
        "answer": "1,800 feet MSL and glide slope interception.\n",
        "choiceone": "BWINE INT and 3,000 feet MSL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "KELEE INT.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Amplitude modulation is:\n",
        "answer": "Varying the amplitude of the carrier wave in accordance with the amplitude of the\naudio modulating signal keeping the carrier frequency constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "Varying the frequency of the carrier wave in accordance with amplitude of the audio\nsignal, keeping the amplitude of the carrier constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Varying the amplitude of the audio frequency in accordance with the amplitude of\nthe carrier wave, keeping the frequency of the carrier constant.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frequency band in which Secondary Surveillance Radar (SSR) operates is:\n",
        "answer": "UHF;\n",
        "choiceone": "VHF;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which four factors affect the accuracy of an NDB?\n",
        "answer": "Quadrantal error, mountain effect, thunderstorm effect, night effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Quadrantal error, night effect, site error, interference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Quadrantal error, night effect, pilotage error, propagation error.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft's heading is 070\u00b0 (M) Variation 10\u00b0E . An NDB bears 200 relative. The RMI\nwill indicate:\n",
        "answer": "270.\n",
        "choiceone": "260;\n",
        "choicetwo": "280;\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "No. 1 pointer of a RMlis tuned to a VOR and no. 2 pointer is tuned to a co-located NDB.\nThe pointers will:\n",
        "answer": "Point in different directions due to, the difference in variation between the aircraft\nand the station.\n",
        "choiceone": "Point in the same direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point in different directions because the VOR uses VHF and the NDB uses LF/MF.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Referring to the\nstation's variation the:\n\nitions on the RMI, if the aircraft's variation\n\n",
        "answer": "The QDM is correct and the relative bearing is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "QDM and the relative bearing is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The QDM is incorrect and the relative bearing is correct.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "The two modulations from which bearing information for the VOR is obtained are:\n",
        "answer": "Reference signal frequency modulated and directional signal apparent amplitude\nmodulated.\n",
        "choiceone": "Both frequency modulated at the transmitter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Reference signal apparent amplitude modulated and directional signal frequency\nmodulated.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is heading 340(M) and is 30 nm from the VOR on a bearing of 142 from the\nVOR. The pilot has selected 146 on the OBS and the TO/FROM indicator shows FROM.\nWhat would the indication be on a 5 dot VOR indicator?\n",
        "answer": "2 dots fly right.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 dots fly left.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4 dots fly right.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "(Please view Annex 062-600184)\nAn aircrafts flying on a MH of 210\u00b0. The magnetic variation at the VOR is 5\u00b0W and at the\naircraft 10\u00b0W.\n\nAccording to the HSI shown at the Annex the aircraft is on radial:\n",
        "answer": "025\n",
        "choiceone": "015\n",
        "choicetwo": "205\n",
        "choicethree": "195\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Heading 041(M) and 20 nm from the VOR on radial 215. With 212\u00b0 selected on the OBS\nand FROM indicated, what information is displayed on the VOR indicator?\n",
        "answer": "Fly left 1.5 dots.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fly right 1.5 dots.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fly left 1 dot.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    },
    {
        "question": "Airborne Search Radar (ASR) is a:\n",
        "answer": "primary radar;\n",
        "choiceone": "secondary radar;\n",
        "choicetwo": "SSR.\n",
        "source": "Completed/NavGen\\nav atpl (9).pdf"
    }
]